9 a.m. in Shanghai.
上午 9 点 在上海。
Shenhua, too. Here in Hong Kong, you're watching the
申花也一样。 在香港，您正在观看
China show. I'm Yvonne Man with David English.
中国秀。 我是伊冯·曼，大卫·英格利希。
We're counting down to the open of markets in Greater China this Monday.
我们正在倒计时 周一大中华区市场。
Let's get to your top stories today. Stocks across the Asia Pacific are
让我们来看看今天的头条新闻。 亚太地区的股票
edging up. A lot of that is to do with the rally in
边缘上升。 这很大程度上与集会有关
Korea. Oil trimming its gains here, the dollar
朝鲜。 石油在这里削减涨幅，美元
falling as markets try to stabilize after the US strikes on a key Iranian
随着市场试图稳定下来而下跌 在美国袭击伊朗重要基地后
export hub. President Trump demanding help from
出口枢纽。 特朗普总统寻求帮助
other countries, including China, to secure the Strait of Hormuz as the world
包括中国在内的其他国家 确保霍尔木兹海峡的安全
grapples with energy supply disruptions. The president also says he could delay a
应对能源供应中断。 总统还表示，他可能会推迟
planned summit with Chinese President Xi Jinping if Beijing does not help unblock
计划与中国国家主席习近平举行峰会 如果北京不帮助解封，习近平
the street. And South Korea is bracing for an oil
街道。 韩国正在为石油做准备
shock by using extra tax revenue to help households and businesses.
通过使用额外的税收来帮助冲击 家庭和企业。
Or exclusive interview with the finance minister coming up.
或者财经专访 部长上来。
Yeah, we're entering a third week of this Iran conflict, and it doesn't seem
是的，我们即将进入第三周 这场伊朗冲突似乎并不
like there is any end in sight here right now.
就像这里看不到尽头一样 现在。
We thought we're going to kick off the show talking about this U.S.
我们以为我们要开始 节目谈论这个美国
attack on this Iranian export hub, and that was probably going to roil markets.
对这个伊朗出口中心的袭击，以及 这可能会扰乱市场。
But I think the last few hours there has been somewhat of a chorus of what
但我认为过去几个小时 有点像合唱什么
President Trump has wanted, urging Neda, urging the likes of China to help in
特朗普总统敦促内达， 敦促中国等国家提供帮助
terms of the reopening of the Strait of Hormuz.
重新开放海峡的条款 霍尔木兹。
But there is also implications for China, right?
但也有影响 中国，对吗？
We're not sure right now whether this this trade talks with President Xi are
我们现在不确定这是否 这次与习主席的贸易谈判
going to happen or not. Yeah, because on Sunday, there was a
是否会发生。 是的，因为周日有一个
meeting, of course, top officials in Paris.
当然，会见高级官员 巴黎。
Right. And by most indications at that point,
正确的。 从当时的大多数迹象来看，
we were those two stories were still largely divorced from each other.
我们还是那两个故事 很大程度上彼此分离。
But now, of course, we now know that those two things are not separate and
但现在，当然，我们现在知道 这两件事不是分开的
that one could affect the other. So markets are trying to figure out.
其中一个可能会影响另一个。 因此市场正在试图弄清楚。
So we're stable right now as far as markets go.
所以我们现在是稳定的 市场行情。
We're trying to figure out, though, whether the premium built in last week
不过，我们正在努力弄清楚， 溢价是否是上周建立的
was enough that there is somewhat visibility on worst case on oil and not
就足够了，有一点 石油最坏情况的可见性，而不是
so much worst case as pertains to the war, because there is no off ramp still
最坏的情况与 战争，因为仍然没有出口匝道
visible there. When you look at the oil price, it does
在那里可见。 当你看石油价格时，你会发现
seem that much is in the price. You know, we open one about 1 to 4.
看来价格里有这么多。 你知道，我们开一个大约 1 到 4 的。
We're at one or two right now here. Yeah.
我们现在就在一两点。 是的。
So things are at least were reversing a little bit here of some of the concerns
所以事情至少正在逆转 这里有一些担忧
around supply disruptions in a light, there was this fear that things will be
围绕供应中断， 人们担心事情会变成这样
more widespread in terms of the the, you know, damage to infrastructure and the
更广泛的是，你 知道，对基础设施和
like. So I think for markets, I mean,
喜欢。 所以我认为对于市场来说，
hopefully at the time for us to look beyond that, in some ways we saw some
希望我们当时能看看 除此之外，在某些方面我们看到了一些
big, big central bank decisions this week to talk about as well.
央行的重大决定 周也可以谈论。
Yeah, unless they tell us to look back at the Iran story, the central banks.
是的，除非他们告诉我们回头看 在伊朗的故事中，央行。
Right. And then that that's really going to
正确的。 然后那真的会
come to fruition. We have some data coming through as well
实现。 我们也收到了一些数据
out of China today that really goes into the economic story we're talking about
今天离开中国，真正进入 我们正在谈论的经济故事
here. We talked about oil.
这里。 我们谈论了石油。
We open above one, two, four. We're below one of the three at the
我们打开上面一、二、四。 我们低于三者之一
moment within the commodities complex. It's now aluminum.
商品综合体内的时刻。 现在是铝的。
That's in focus, too, given the set of second degree implications as it
考虑到这组 二级影响
pertains to that specific part of the energy market.
属于该特定部分 能源市场。
The commodities market were up 1% in London.
大宗商品市场上涨 1% 伦敦。
We're looking at a contract as well when things come fully online in Shanghai.
我们也在考虑合同时 上海的一切都完全在线化了。
Right. The effects and rate story is one where
正确的。 效果和比率的故事是这样的：
on Friday the dollar hit the highest level of the year.
周五美元触及最高点 年的水平。
We're giving up getting back some of that strength.
我们正在放弃取回一些 那种力量。
Yes, we are close to 160. That's the level we're talking about
是的，我们已经接近 160 了。 这就是我们所说的水平
here. Separate scenes of dollar yen, euro
这里。 美元日元、欧元的单独场景
dollar in focus. So we have a flurry of central bank
美元成为焦点。 所以我们有一系列央行
decisions this week. Equity markets here, the Nikkei costs
本周的决定。 这里是股票市场，日经指数成本
Taiwan coming online, US futures on your screens.
台湾上线，美国期货上你 屏幕。
And a lot of that, of course, has to do with the cost p and the rally there.
当然，其中很多都必须做 成本 p 和那里的反弹。
Taiwan is also opening up 1%. And just a glance at futures going into
台湾也开放了1%。 只需浏览一下未来的情况
the open today, a 50 futures and you have shanghai oil and shanghai aluminum
今天开盘，50 期货和你 有上海石油、上海铝业
one 4.7% to the upside. And it's looking like we are set for
上涨 4.7%。 看起来我们已经准备好了
gains here in greater China, at least for today.
至少在大中华区取得了进展 今天。
Yep. And on your agenda here today, as you
是的。 在今天的议程上，正如你们
mentioned, it is about the state of these US-China trade talks as well with
提到的，这是关于状态 这些中美贸易谈判以及
the effort to say, look, President Trump says he could delay it if China does not
努力说，看，特朗普总统 表示如果中国不这样做他可以推迟
help out when it comes to reopening the Strait of Hormuz.
在重新开放时提供帮助 霍尔木兹海峡。
That activity data, we got a big data dump coming through at the top of the
那活动数据，我们得到了一个大数据 转储从顶部通过
hour as well. Home prices coming through the bottom of
小时也是如此。 房价已见底
this hours. Look up for that first in terms of what
这几个小时。 首先从什么方面查找
we could get in terms of data. We're watching everything from aluminum
我们可以得到数据。 我们正在关注铝的一切
and really zinc. So, you know, we we talked when we went
还有真正的锌。 所以，你知道，我们去的时候聊过
beyond the whole oil discussion. Gas last week was really this week might
超出了整个石油讨论范围。 上周的天然气真的是本周可能
have been more about zinc just given some of the supply disruptions that even
刚刚给出了更多关于锌的信息 一些供应中断甚至
China is facing when it comes to getting access to some of these zinc
中国在获取资源方面面临着 获得其中一些锌
concentrates in the Middle East as well. The 200 day moving average in the size
也集中在中东地区。 200日移动平均线的大小
certainly is one thing to watch there. And of course, we've got some earnings
那里当然是值得关注的一件事。 当然，我们也有一些收入
coming through here today. Yeah, late motor CSPs, which is a farm
今天经过这里。 是的，晚期电机 CSP，这是一个农场
pharma play, of course, Sinopec Oil Fields, which is of course one of the
制药业，当然是中石化石油 字段，这当然是其中之一
units there, the bigger one listed onshore.
那里的单位，列出的较大的单位 陆上。
Lots to watch there today. But yeah, let's get the latest Here is
今天那里有很多值得一看的地方。 但是，是的，让我们获取最新的信息，这是
here. President Trump, when you talk about
这里。 特朗普总统，当你谈论
late just in the last year or so, President Trump here is demanding that
就在去年晚些时候， 特朗普总统在这里要求
other countries contribute to the defense of the Strait of Hormuz, which
其他国家也做出了贡献 保卫霍尔木兹海峡，
remains effectively shut. Oil tankers.
仍然有效关闭。 油轮。
We heard from him earlier saying that China should play a more active role in
我们早些时候听他说 中国应发挥更加积极的作用
the region. They should come.
该地区。 他们应该来。
In my opinion, it never made sense for years.
在我看来，这从来没有意义 年。
If you go back and look at what I've said years ago, he said, why are we
如果你回去看看我做了什么 几年前他说，我们为什么
gaining history when it's really there for China and many of the countries?
当历史真实存在时获得历史 对于中国和许多国家来说？
Meanwhile, the OFT is reporting that he could delay his much anticipated summit
与此同时，OFT 报道称，他 可能会推迟他备受期待的峰会
with Chinese President Xi Jinping if Beijing doesn't help unblock the strait.
如果与中国国家主席习近平 北京并没有帮助解除海峡封锁。
Let's bring in our team now, our Bloomberg managing editor, Jill Jesus
现在让我们带上我们的团队，我们的 彭博社总编辑吉尔·耶稣
and our China correspondent below with the latest.
以及我们的驻华记者如下 最新的。
Jill, I'll start with you. You know, of course, we were supposed to
吉尔，我就从你开始吧。 你知道，当然，我们应该
talk about this big, you know, attack on Kharg Island, but now it seems like
谈论这个大的，你知道的，攻击 哈格岛，但现在看来
you're getting more of this urgency from President Trump to get other nations
你越来越感受到这种紧迫感 特朗普总统要求其他国家
involved in reopening the Strait of Hormuz.
参与重新开放海峡 霍尔木兹。
How high of a hurdle would that be? I mean, at this point, have on it's
那会有多高的障碍呢？ 我的意思是，在这一点上，有它的
really difficult to tell just. But you can see just from, you know,
确实很难说清楚而已。 但你可以看到，你知道，
some of these comments from Trump that, you know, he's he's using the word
特朗普的一些评论是， 你知道，他正在用这个词
demanding. He's demanding that countries kind of
要求很高。 他要求各国
get involved with them. He's sort of protecting the Strait of
与他们交往。 他有点保护海峡
Hormuz. And then obviously, some of this broader
霍尔木兹。 显然，其中一些更广泛的
conversations about coalition building. I mean, this is a really, really tough
关于联盟建设的对话。 我的意思是，这真的非常非常艰难
task that Trump has in front of him. And I think, you know, what you're
特朗普摆在他面前的任务。 我想，你知道，你是什么
seeing here is that all signs point to him being the one that ultimately has
看到这里，所有迹象都表明 他是最终拥有的人
the power to kind of end this war. But it's kind of unclear what exactly he
结束这场战争的力量。 但有点不清楚他到底是什么
really wants from this. Right.
真的很想从这个。 正确的。
I mean, you've had some shifting, you know, conflicting messaging from the
我的意思是，你已经发生了一些转变，你 知道，来自冲突的消息
Trump administration about what exactly it is that, you know, they're ultimately
特朗普政府到底想做什么 你知道，他们最终是
looking to achieve here. Certainly, you know, the end of any kind
希望在这里实现。 当然，你知道，任何形式的终结
of nuclear weapons program in Iran is a key consideration here.
伊朗的核武器计划是 这里的关键考虑因素。
But he also said in those comments on Air Force One, there were some other
但他在这些评论中也表示 空军一号，还有其他一些
things that they were looking at, but he didn't exactly make clear what it was he
他们正在看的东西，但他 并没有明确说明他是什么
was talking about. You know, there's some ideas floating
正在谈论。 你知道，有一些想法浮现
around about the possibility for regime change.
关于政权的可能性 改变。
But of course, we saw what happened with the old supreme leader being replaced by
但当然，我们看到了发生的事情 旧最高领导人被取代
his son, who, if anything, is, you know, more aggressive on some of these
他的儿子，如果有的话，就是，你知道， 对其中一些更加积极
tactics. So if you're something some of these
策略。 所以如果你是其中的一些人
other nations that's listening to these Trump comments on protecting the Strait
其他正在聆听这些的国家 特朗普关于保护海峡的评论
of Hormuz and securing passage for those ships for some kind of a coalition
霍尔木兹并确保这些人的通行 为某种联盟提供船只
building, you might want a little bit more out of Donald Trump himself on what
建筑，你可能想要一点 更多来自唐纳德·特朗普本人
exactly that clear path forward out of the world looks like before you really
正是那条清晰的前进道路 世界看起来就像在你面前一样
get on board. Maidment I'll bring you in.
上船。 女仆我带你进去。
What's happening in the Middle East, which seems to now be affecting whether
中东正在发生什么， 现在这似乎正在影响是否
or not we'll be having a summit between the two.
或不，我们将在之间举行峰会 两个。
What do we know about that? Well, on the policy market, the bets are
我们对此了解多少？ 那么，在政策市场上，赌注是
less than 50% that Trump is going to arrive by end of March.
不到特朗普打算的50% 三月底抵达。
But, yes, there has been a lot of speculation when the Iran war first
但是，是的，已经有很多 伊朗战争第一次爆发时的猜测
broke out whether that summit will be derailed.
爆发了这次峰会是否会举行 出轨了。
And this is the first time we're hearing from President Trump that he might delay
这是我们第一次听到 特朗普总统表示他可能会推迟
the summit. And the precondition here is that China
峰会。 而这里的前提是中国
contributes to keeping the Strait of Hormuz open and send warships to that
有助于维护海峡 霍尔木兹打开并派遣军舰前往那里
area. But if you just read those, the linked
区域。 但如果你只是阅读这些内容，链接的
media reports so far, China views the root cause of the conflict as the US and
据媒体报道，中方认为 冲突的根源在于美国和
Israel attacks on Iran. And they view this move by President
以色列袭击伊朗。 他们认为总统的这一举动
Trump essentially as dragging other countries in a war that it's started.
特朗普本质上是在拖累其他人 战争已经开始的国家。
And so far, China's stance on Iran has been no more than rhetorical support.
迄今为止，中国对伊朗的立场 只不过是口头上的支持。
Right. And it's very unlikely, at least in the
正确的。 而且这种情况不太可能发生，至少在
past, China has been quite willing to put boots on the ground and put military
过去，中国一直非常愿意 把靴子放在地上，把军事
backing in a conflict that is far away from home.
支持遥远的冲突 从家里。
So it's not clear how willing they are to really accede to President Trump's
所以不清楚他们有多愿意 真正接受特朗普总统的
request. But, you know, two weeks is a long time,
要求。 但是，你知道，两周是很长的时间，
and maybe that could be some sort of face saving gesture in the lead up to
也许这可能是某种 保全面子的手势
the summit. And potentially it could still happen.
峰会。 而且这种情况仍有可能发生。
It's really hard to say at this point. Do you see China play any role in this
现在真的很难说。 您认为中国在这方面发挥什么作用吗？
whole Iran situation? Well, I think the one thing that you
整个伊朗局势？ 好吧，我认为你做的一件事是
have to keep in mind when it comes to China, too, is that, you know, what kind
必须记住 中国也是，你知道，什么样的
of leverage do they have in any kind of negotiations here?
他们有任何形式的杠杆作用吗？ 在这里谈判？
Right. I mean, you can make the argument that
正确的。 我的意思是，你可以这样说
after, you know, Trump's tariff regime was essentially struck down by the
在特朗普的关税制度之后 基本上被击倒了
Supreme Court of the United States and that he's now pursuing some other
美国最高法院和 他现在正在追求其他人
options to kind of get tariffs in place, that China, which did kind of emerge, is
实施关税的选项， 中国确实出现了，
like a pretty significant victor in everything last year when all that chaos
就像一个相当重要的胜利者 去年的一切，当时所有的混乱
was flying around, might have, you know, a bit more leverage when it comes to
正在飞来飞去，可能，你知道， 涉及到时多一点杠杆
actually getting, you know, Trump to, you know, to the table to talk about
实际上，你知道，特朗普 你知道，到桌子上来谈谈
what they want to do. So I do think that that's part of this.
他们想做什么。 所以我确实认为这是其中的一部分。
But I think, you know, you know, it's been said, you know, there's a lot here
但我认为，你知道，你知道，这是 有人说过，你知道，这里有很多东西
that China might not necessarily want to get involved with and that isn't
中国可能不一定愿意 参与其中，但那不是
necessarily in their best interests. So you do have these pretty strong
必然符合他们的最大利益。 所以你确实有这些很强大的
comments from Trump. But, you know, how powerful of leverage
来自特朗普的评论。 但是，你知道，杠杆的力量有多大
is it actually for Trump to say, you know, maybe I just won't go to Beijing?
特朗普实际上是想说，你 知道吗，也许我只是不会去北京？
So I think that that's a pretty significant question here.
所以我认为这是一个漂亮的 这里有一个重要的问题。
Assuming this summit is still taking place.
假设本次峰会仍在进行 地方。
We had talks in Paris, high level talks. What do we get out of that?
我们在巴黎进行了高层会谈。 我们从中得到什么？
Yeah. So the fun day is over.
是的。 这样愉快的一天就结束了。
That was on Sunday, 6 hours of talks. But neither side spoke to the media on
那是周日，会谈持续了 6 个小时。 但双方均未向媒体发表谈话
the way in and out of the venue today. They're going to continue the talks
今天进出会场的路。 他们将继续会谈
again. But so far, Reuters has reported, based
再次。 但到目前为止，据路透社报道，
on the sources, that the talks were candid and constructive.
消息人士称，会谈正在进行中 坦诚且有建设性。
And it seems like China is showing some signs of goodwill, saying that they are
中国似乎正在展示一些 善意的迹象，说他们是
open to buying more agricultural products beyond soybeans, including
愿意购买更多农产品 大豆以外的产品，包括
things like poultry, beef, non soybean roll crops, for example.
家禽、牛肉、非大豆等 例如，卷作物。
And they are still pledging to fulfill their commitment that 25 million tons of
他们仍然承诺履行 他们承诺2500万吨
soybeans per year over the next three years.
未来三年每年大豆产量 年。
We understand from the Reuters report that the U.S.
我们从路透社的报道中了解到 美国
is also pressing China to buy more U.S. oil and natural gas as well.
还敦促中国购买更多美国产品 还有石油和天然气。
So the US clearly also emerging a winner in this Iran conflict, given they are
所以美国显然也成为了赢家 在这场伊朗冲突中，鉴于他们
the largest exporter of LNG globally. And there's also the Boeing deal on the
全球最大的液化天然气出口国。 还有波音公司的交易
table. And according to Reuters, both sides are
桌子。 据路透社报道，双方
looking at coming out. With technical talks, a so-called Board
看着出来。 通过技术会谈，所谓的董事会
of Investments and Board of Trade. And these two mechanisms will be talks
投资和贸易委员会。 这两个机制将进行会谈
that allow them to identify sectors and products where they can increase trade
使他们能够识别部门并 可以增加贸易的产品
to balance that trade relationship. The Board of Investment would deal with
以平衡贸易关系。 投资委员会将处理
discretionary investment issues, and we know that China so far has been very
全权委托投资问题，我们 要知道中国到目前为止已经非常
keen to put money in the US, but they have faced a lot of scrutiny from Sophie
热衷于把钱投入美国，但他们 受到了苏菲的很多审视
as they face a lot of restrictions. So we'll see if this actually opens up
因为他们面临很多限制。 所以我们会看看这是否真的开放
space for both sides to mutually invest in each other's countries.
双方相互投资空间 在彼此的国家。
All right. Thank you.
好的。 谢谢。
I our correspondent Vivian Loh there and our managing editor, Jill De Su, is
我台通讯员 Vivian Loh 在那里， 我们的总编辑 Jill De Su 是
joining us here on set. And as the war drags on, we've got to
加入我们的拍摄现场。 随着战争的持续，我们必须
talk a bit more about what this means for the world of equities.
多谈谈这意味着什么 对于股票世界来说。
Jp morgan's Asia equity and quant strategist Miso Dass joins us to assess
摩根大通的亚洲股票和量化 策略师 Miso Dass 与我们一起评估
these volatile market positioning, what to do next here.
这些波动的市场定位是什么 接下来要做的就是在这里。
And now they're talking about this wall of liquidity for equities.
现在他们正在谈论这堵墙 股票的流动性。
He's starting to see traction around that sort of theme.
他开始看到周围的吸引力 那种主题。
Yeah, and I think they're overweight
是的， 我认为他们超重了
materials. And to what extent has that trader
材料。 该交易员在多大程度上
already run its course? And what are the sort of how does that
已经走完自己的路了吗？ 那是怎样的
trade expand in terms of the tactical opportunities that have arisen given
贸易在战术上扩大 已出现的机会
events in the Middle East more with MC? So in a moment, of course, coming down
中东的活动多用MC？ 所以一会儿，当然，下来
to the open of trade, we're called higher price futures.
为了贸易的开放，我们被称为 期货价格更高。
We have a lot of data coming through, plus some earnings in Greater China,
我们有大量的数据经过， 加上大中华区的部分盈利，
4/10 of 1%. Opening bell, 18 minutes away.
1% 的 4/10。 开场钟声，还有 18 分钟路程。
This is the China show.
这就是中国秀。
Welcome back. The question Energy Barbell Global
欢迎回来。 问题 能量 Barbell Global
Markets. Let me widen the viewpoint there across
市场。 让我拓宽视野
markets is what exactly are we seeing in terms of tanker traffic on the Strait of
市场正是我们所看到的 海峡油轮运输条件
Hormuz? Right.
霍尔木兹？ 正确的。
You put together everything and that's a map.
你把所有东西放在一起，那就是 地图。
Of course, that's cargo, of course, which was a weekend, subjected a barrage
当然，那是货物，当然， 那是一个周末，遭到了弹幕的攻击
of military action from the US upward, of course, into the Persian Gulf.
从美国向上的军事行动， 当然是进入波斯湾。
There's a straight this is the Oman Gulf and this is data from the last 30 days,
有一条直道，这是阿曼湾 这是过去 30 天的数据，
mind you. So if you do see some vessels there that
请注意。 所以如果你确实在那里看到一些船只
effectively says that they were there, it doesn't mean they're there right now.
有效地表明他们在那里， 这并不意味着他们现在就在那里。
But you do see, of course, this tanker traffic that just parts and not being
但你当然看到了这艘油轮 交通只是分开而不是
able to pass through a lot of reports out in the weekend.
能够通过大量的报告 周末出去。
Right. You know, if you have any linkages to
正确的。 你知道，如果你有任何联系
China or Russia, that gives you free passage or the report suggests that
中国或俄罗斯，给你自由 段落或报告表明
everybody but American and Israeli linked tankers can get free passage.
除了美国人和以色列人之外的所有人 连接的油轮可以自由通行。
But here's what the data is telling us. And we have real time data here on the
但这是数据告诉我们的。 我们这里有实时数据
Bloomberg to tell you that. Let's flip the page, please.
彭博社来告诉你。 请让我们翻页吧。
Okay. So what we have is bi directional east
好的。 所以我们拥有的是双向向东
to west, west to east, 24 hour rolling data every 30 minutes.
向西，从西向东，24小时滚动 每 30 分钟一次数据。
And what the data shows is there has been effectively no, not a single while,
数据显示有 实际上没有，没有一段时间，
only a one or two, one or two, but effectively near zero in as far as the
只有一两个，一两个，但是 实际上接近于零
vessel count on the Strait of Hormuz in the last 30 minutes or so.
霍尔木兹海峡的船只数量 最后30分钟左右。
In fact, the last 24 hours shows you give or take about two, maybe three.
事实上，过去 24 小时告诉你 给或拿大约两个，也许三个。
But it just goes to show that the choke point remains choked Iran.
但这只是表明窒息 伊朗的重点仍然是窒息。
Yeah, And as the IAEA said last week. Right.
是的，正如国际原子能机构上周所说。 正确的。
In terms of supply disruptions, this is the worst that they've seen in global
就供应中断而言，这是 他们在全球见过的最糟糕的情况
oil markets ever. And we continue to track, of course, of
石油市场有史以来。 当然，我们会继续追踪
damage and the like. Let's bring in our oil and shipping
损坏等。 让我们把石油和船运进来
reporter Raymond. So and he joins us from Singapore.
记者雷蒙德. 所以他从新加坡加入我们。
Well, obviously there's there's comments from what we heard from President Trump
嗯，显然有评论 根据我们从特朗普总统那里听到的消息
this morning about me, possibly DiMaggio demanding countries to help reopen the
今天早上关于我的事，可能是迪马吉奥 要求各国帮助重新开放
Strait of Hormuz. There also was that attack of that
霍尔木兹海峡。 还有那次攻击
Iranian export hub. I'm just wondering, what is your team
伊朗出口中心。 我只是想知道你的团队是什么
really tracking the most here this morning?
真的在这里追踪最多的这个 早上？
I think as of now, we still don't see any traffic going through the Strait of
我想到目前为止，我们还没有看到 任何通过海峡的交通
Hormuz. And definitely Trump is feeling the
霍尔木兹。 特朗普肯定感觉到了
pressure on that. He's seen how the closure of the Strait
对此的压力。 他亲眼目睹了海峡的关闭
of Hormuz is has impacted oil prices, and therefore, that's why he's
霍尔木兹的影响影响了石油价格， 因此，这就是为什么他
suggesting that countries send in some naval escorts through the street to
建议各国派遣一些 海军护航穿过街道
ensure safe passage. But how that can happen in reality
确保安全通行。 但这在现实中怎么可能发生
really remains to be seen. No one wants to send in a very high
是否真的还有待观察。 没有人愿意发送非常高的
price on naval assets to open them to possible attacks.
海军资产价格 让他们遭受可能的攻击。
Right. So as you've mentioned, tanker traffic
正确的。 正如您所提到的，油轮运输
through the Strait of Hormuz has basically fallen to zero.
穿过霍尔木兹海峡 基本跌为零。
But there are a few important caveats over here.
但有一些重要的注意事项 在这里。
Firstly, some of those ships might have gone through dock.
首先，其中一些船只可能有 经过码头。
That means they turn off their transponder signals to protect
这意味着他们关掉他们的 应答器信号保护
themselves or they may be part of the dark fleet that Iran Iranian fleet uses
他们自己或者他们可能是 伊朗 伊朗舰队使用的黑暗舰队
to export oil out of the Strait of Hormuz.
从海峡出口石油 霍尔木兹。
And also the other big thing is that this sort of signal jamming across the
另一件大事是 这种信号干扰
Persian Gulf. This is not just because Iran is trying
波斯湾。 这不仅仅是因为伊朗正在努力
to perhaps affect ships safety of passage, but also other countries do
可能会影响船舶的安全 通过，但其他国家也这样做
engage in signal jamming to protect themselves during times of warfare.
进行信号干扰以保护 战争时期的自己。
You know. That's an important caveat there.
你知道。 这是一个重要的警告。
In fact, anecdotal, you know, some of our colleagues I know some people, of
事实上，有一些轶事，你知道， 我们的同事 我认识一些人
course, in that part of the world, when you run your location on Google Maps,
当然，在世界的那个地方，当 您在 Google 地图上运行您的位置，
you are nowhere near where you actually are, which is a good pointer to really
你离你实际的地方还很远 是，这是一个很好的指针
make. Well, and what do we know now?
制作。 好吧，我们现在知道什么？
Give us an update on any major damage to oil infrastructure over the weekend.
请向我们通报任何重大损坏的最新情况 周末的石油基础设施。
Do we see any developments as far as that specific front is concerned?
我们是否看到任何进展 涉及到那个特定的战线？
Exactly. I think the biggest one we've seen so
确切地。 我认为我们见过的最大的
far is Fujairah. That's in the UAE, but it's outside of
远处就是富查伊拉。 那是在阿联酋，但在国外
Strait of Hormuz. So it sits on the Gulf of Oman and it's
霍尔木兹海峡。 所以它坐落在阿曼湾
a key oil export heart for the UAE, because even though a lot of these oil
阿联酋重要的石油出口中心， 因为即使有很多这样的油
exporters rely on the Persian Gulf to export all through which the Strait of
出口商依赖波斯湾 出口全部通过海峡
Hormuz is a crucial corridor. But since the closure of the Strait of
霍尔木兹是一条重要的走廊。 但自从海峡关闭后
Hormuz, the UAE has been able to redirect some of its crude exports to
阿联酋霍尔木兹已经能够 将其部分原油出口重定向至
Fujairah to bypass Hormuz. And those drone attacks that we saw over
富查伊拉绕过霍尔木兹。 我们看到的那些无人机袭击
the weekend that really took down the port itself.
真正让人们失望的周末 端口本身。
Operations were suspended for about a day or so.
业务暂停约一小时 一天左右。
It's it's it's a small drone attack, but it could show what Iran can do, even
这是一次小型无人机攻击，但是 它可以展示伊朗可以做什么，甚至
though these port export terminals, this oil export terminal, sorry, are sitting
虽然这些港口出口码头，这 石油出口码头，抱歉，正在坐
outside of home with Iran to affect some of those exports.
在国外与伊朗的接触会影响到一些人 这些出口。
Well, there's been some reports as well of a rolling vessel still being able to
嗯，也有一些报道 滚动船舶仍然能够
go through. You know, there are also reports that
经过。 要知道，还有报道称
China or Chinese sort of ships are getting exemptions as well.
中国或中国种类的船只是 也获得豁免。
What more do we know at this point? I think so far what we can tell,
此时我们还知道什么？ 我认为到目前为止我们可以告诉的，
frankly, is ships do signal that they have Chinese ownership.
坦率地说，船舶确实发出信号表明它们 拥有中国所有权。
We've seen bulk carrier vessels exiting the Strait of Hormuz signaling Chinese
我们已经看到散货船退出 霍尔木兹海峡向中国发出信号
ownership or manager. So it's it's hard to draw a direct
所有权或管理者。 所以很难直接画出
correlation between that and a tacit agreement between Tehran and Beijing to
与默契之间的相关性 德黑兰与北京达成协议
allow Chinese ships to safely go through.
让中国船只安全航行 通过。
But safe to say that many ships and ship owners are recognizing the fact that
但可以肯定地说，许多船只和船只 业主们正在认识到这样一个事实
signaling that you have no relation to the US or maybe Israel
表明你有 与美国或以色列无关
will perhaps give you some form of safe passage through the strait.
也许会给你某种形式的安全 通过海峡。
But what we do know for sure is that India has managed to get some ships
但我们确实知道的是 印度已成功获得一些船只
through the Strait of Hormuz, as we've reported over the past week.
穿过霍尔木兹海峡 过去一周的报道。
Well, and thank you, Will Ensign there in Singapore for us, getting us updated
好吧，谢谢你，威尔少尉 在新加坡为我们提供最新信息
and really the important context as far as the oil tanker traffic is concerned.
到目前为止，确实是重要的背景 就油轮运输而言。
More updates, of course, coming from our oil team in a moment.
当然，更多更新来自我们 石油队一会儿。
Right. More on the story, right to South Korea.
正确的。 更多关于这个故事的内容，请前往韩国。
Massive energy importer. The market apart from today, of course,
大型能源进口国。 当然，除了今天的市场，
has taken quite a bit of a hit there. Well, the country will be using extra
那里受到了相当大的打击。 好吧，国家将使用额外的
tax revenue to then fund this supplementary budget in a bid here to
税收收入然后为此提供资金 补充预算旨在
cushion really the homes businesses from rising energy prices triggered by what's
真正为家庭企业提供缓冲 能源价格上涨的原因是什么
taking place in the in the Middle East. It's finance minister who spoke with us
发生在中东。 与我们交谈的是财政部长
exclusively on Friday. To a man to no song here to corroborate
仅限周五。 给一个男人没有歌曲可以佐证
it can get to them right away. Right now, the Middle East situation is
它可以立即到达他们那里。 当前，中东局势
overshadowing the global economy. The government's top priority right now
给全球经济蒙上阴影。 政府当前的首要任务
is responding to the Middle East situation in the short term, while
正在回应中东 短期内的情况，同时
reducing Korea's structural dependence on oil over the medium to long term.
减少韩国的结构性依赖 中长期来看石油。
Which is why you just announced a fuel price cap.
这就是为什么你刚刚宣布了一种燃料 价格上限。
Why in this specific measure, instead of others more potentially broadly or more
为什么在这个具体措施中，而不是 其他更广泛或更广泛的潜力
targeted measures to support the economy?
有针对性的支持措施 经济？
Isn't it? Currently the imported oil is from
不是吗？ 目前进口石油来自
before the Middle East conflict during this two week period when imports have
中东冲突之前 这两周期间进口量
been halted. It will come in at a higher price.
被叫停。 它将以更高的价格进入。
However, if the future imports become even more expensive, the government
然而，如果未来的进口量变成 更贵的是政府
plans to raise the price proposal accordingly to compensate.
计划提高价格建议 相应地进行补偿。
The government plans to decide at that time whether to reduce taxes again
政府计划届时做出决定 是否再次减税的时间
on health care. Would it submit that if you actually
关于医疗保健。 如果你真的
need to help the refiners, does that mean that the government will be using
需要帮助炼油厂吗？ 意味着政府将使用
its own budget in order to do that? And how are you planning to pay for that
自己的预算才能做到这一点？ 您打算如何支付费用
cost increase or might not get equal? So therefore, if refiners incur losses
成本增加还是可能不相等？ 因此，如果炼油厂蒙受损失
during this process, the government intends to compensate for those losses.
在此过程中，政府 打算补偿这些损失。
And that was South Korean Finance Minister Kun Cho there speaking
这就是韩国金融 曹昆部长在现场讲话
exclusively to Bloomberg. And about much more from that
彭博社独家报道。 还有更多
conversation later on this hour. Right.
这个小时晚些时候的谈话。 正确的。
Just going into the open today, 8 minutes to the opening bell.
今天8点刚开放 距离开场钟还有几分钟。
A preview, a full preview of the day ahead.
预览，当天的完整预览 前面。
It's coming up next. This is the China show.
接下来就到了。 这就是中国秀。
All right. We're also watching, of course, this
好的。 当然，我们也在关注这个
data dump that's coming through the top of the hour.
来自顶部的数据转储 小时的。
When it comes to industrial production, we're expecting a print of about 5.3%.
在工业生产方面， 我们预计印刷率约为 5.3%。
We're still negative when it comes to fixed asset investments.
我们仍然持消极态度 固定资产投资。
The retail sales side, you know, a two and a half percent print, which is
零售销售方面，你知道，有两个 百分之半的打印，即
already a little bit of a improvement from the previous, but still not quite
已经有了一点点的进步 与之前相比，但仍然不完全
good. So certainly we'll see what that means.
好的。 所以我们肯定会看到这意味着什么。
I mean, we have home prices coming through as well.
我的意思是，我们的房价即将上涨 也通过。
And we're expecting and, you know, maybe another 34th straight month of
我们期待着，你知道，也许 又是连续第 34 个月
contraction when it comes to home prices.
回家时收缩 价格。
Yeah, the momentum there seems to I mean, there was a period of time last
是的，我觉得那里的势头 意思是，上次有一段时间
year when it seemed the momentum was shifting.
那一年似乎势头强劲 转移。
But going into 2026, things have obviously pulled pull back to the
但进入 2026 年，情况发生了变化 明显拉扯拉回
downside here. It's worth pointing out, too, when you
缺点在这里。 也值得指出的是，当您
look at the data, I saw two things Rates of PMI did signal contraction and this
看一下数据，我看到了两件事 PMI 确实发出收缩信号，这
is Jen and Fed numbers coming through just to sort of even out seasonal
Jen 和美联储的数据出来了吗 只是为了平衡季节性
aberrations between of course where you have that the the the long holiday that
当然你所在的地方之间存在偏差 有那个长假吗
time of the year. Right.
一年中的某个时间。 正确的。
A couple of other things going into the open today.
还有一些其他的事情要考虑 今天开放。
It's worth pointing out that the CSI 300 was actually up slightly last week.
值得指出的是，沪深300指数 实际上上周略有上涨。
Right. It just tells you about the, I guess,
正确的。 它只是告诉你，我猜，
relative resiliency of the specific market.
具体的相对弹性 市场。
But still, of course, broadly speaking, still down, though, for the last few
但当然，从广义上讲， 不过，最近几年仍然处于低位
weeks or so, Hang Seng index closed below the 200 day moving average on
几周左右，恒生指数收盘 低于200日移动平均线
Friday. Pre-market suggests not a lot of
星期五。 上市前建议不多
movement going into the session today, maybe early outperformers in the form of
今天会议的动议， 也许早期的表现优于
some tech plays. We'll get to that in a moment.
一些科技剧。 我们稍后会讨论这个问题。
In terms of the agenda today, just to recap some of these things, we talked
就今天的议程而言， 回顾一下其中一些事情，我们谈过
about the talks, activity numbers and home prices.
关于会谈、活动数量和 房价。
Aluminum should be coming up on your screens and also zinc.
铝应该出现在你的 屏幕和锌。
So that's now the this expanded hit to the commodity company aluminum, because
这就是现在这个扩大的打击 商品公司铝，因为
in particular it came to that Bahrain smelter that has a phase production
特别是巴林 具有阶段性生产的冶炼厂
shutdown and this is one of the world's largest single site smelters of the
关闭，这是世界上最关闭的之一 最大的单一地点冶炼厂
metals. So Chinese alumina stocks are very much
金属。 所以中国氧化铝库存非常多
in focus. You mentioned zinc as well, just given
焦点集中。 你也提到了锌，刚刚给出
you Chinese refineries and what their access to zinc right now is also quite
你们中国的炼油厂以及他们的 现在获得锌的机会也很大
uncertain here. Tuesday, moving hours, as we talked
这里不确定。 周二，移动时间，正如我们所说
about stocks to watch certainly is the aluminum side of things you are seeing.
关于股票值得关注的肯定是 您所看到的事物的铝面。
The likes of Hong Chao, Chinalco are slightly up here this morning.
洪超、中铝等 今天早上这里略有上升。
Oil stocks could be going all over the place, just given that we saw the price
石油库存可能会遍布全球 地方，只是鉴于我们看到了价格
of crude basically were at one. It was six at one point a few hours ago.
原油基本上为一。 几个小时前的某一时刻，时间是六点。
Now we've kind of settled near the $100 mark here, just given what we've seen
现在我们已经稳定在 100 美元附近 在这里做标记，只是给出我们所看到的
with President Trump. And, you know, this this push for more
与特朗普总统。 而且，你知道，这推动了更多
coordination or coalition when it comes to these exports around the Strait of
协调或联合 对海峡周围的这些出口
Hormuz. Yes.
霍尔木兹。 是的。
We're not seeing a whole lot of movement when it comes to some of these big oil
我们没有看到太多的运动 当谈到其中一些大型石油时
names and show me it coming out with a new SUV.
名字并告诉我它出来了 新的SUV。
So we'll definitely watch that stock here at the Abby Space this morning.
所以我们一定会关注该股票 今天早上在艾比空间。
The orbit is next.
接下来是轨道。
Welcome back. You're watching the China show.
欢迎回来。 你正在看中国节目。
We are set to open up in about 40 seconds from now.
我们预计 40 年后开放 从现在开始几秒钟。
Mixed bag. We're also going to get some numbers
混合袋。 我们还将得到一些数字
coming through here in the form of new home prices, while home prices,
以新的形式来到这里 房价，而房价，
generally speaking, in a couple of seconds and the top of the next hour,
一般来说，在几个 秒和下一小时的最高点，
the activity numbers are coming through as well.
活动数量正在通过 以及。
And the numbers do suggest that we might be still speeding up, but stuck in the
这些数字确实表明我们可能 仍在加速，但陷入困境
low gear sort of mode for the economy the first two months or so.
低档经济模式 前两个月左右。
Of course, we talked about these with the Jan and Fed numbers here.
当然，我们讨论过这些 这里是一月份和美联储的数据。
So we'll see how that all plays out here.
所以我们会看看这一切如何进行 在这里。
But certainly what we're turning more our attention to is whether this whole
但我们肯定会改变更多 我们关注的是这整个
situation in Iran is going to impact those trade talks between President Xi
伊朗局势将受到影响 习主席之间的贸易谈判
and President Trump in just a few weeks. That seems to be the next element in
特朗普总统在短短几周内。 这似乎是下一个元素
this story. Now, according to what President Trump
这个故事。 现在，根据特朗普总统的说法
said to the F.T. here this morning, that they could
对英国《金融时报》说 今天早上在这里，他们可以
possibly delay this meeting with China here if, in fact, China does not help,
可能会推迟与中国的这次会议 事实上，如果中国不提供帮助，
along with narrow nations in on blocking the Strait of Hormuz.
与狭隘国家一起封锁 霍尔木兹海峡。
So in terms of what we're seeing across equities here, you know, China's assets
所以就我们所看到的而言 这里的股票，你知道，中国的资产
have been seen largely as that sort of safe haven.
很大程度上被视为这样的 避风港。
And we're seeing it pretty flat here right now when it comes to onshore.
我们在这里看到它非常平坦 现在说到陆上。
We're watching very closely, of course, Shanghai crude.
当然，我们正在密切关注 上海原油。
It is sort of slightly elevated, up some 3%.
它有点高，上升一些 3%。
But certainly we've already have seen Brent and WTI come off a little bit from
但我们肯定已经看到了 布伦特原油和 WTI 略有下跌
the initial sort of moves this morning. Just given what we heard from President
今天早上的初步举动。 刚刚我们从总统那里听到的消息
Trump and this urgency to really kind of help out and what's going on in that key
特朗普和这种紧迫感 帮忙看看这个键发生了什么
vital waterway. Watching, watching all things aluminum,
重要水道。 看着，看着所有铝制的东西，
certainly that has been elevated. Given that we talked about that Bahrain
当然，这个数字已经提高了。 鉴于我们谈到了巴林
smelter and really the phased production cuts there.
冶炼厂和真正的分阶段生产 在那里切掉。
Zinc, as we've talked about, is probably the next thing to watch.
正如我们所讨论的，锌可能是 接下来要看的事情。
So, you know, when it comes to these large caps, it's a mixed picture.
所以，你知道，当谈到这些时 大写字母，这是一个复杂的情况。
There's not a whole lot of conviction. It needless to say.
没有太多的信念。 不用说。
Cabochon, Texas, slightly lower here with the watching, of course, some of
德克萨斯州凸圆面，此处略低 当然，随着观看，一些
these consumption names. Given that, you know, really there has
这些消费名称。 鉴于此，你知道，确实有
been a disappointment from NBC and the like when it came to the consumption
NBC 和 就像谈到消费时
side. Take a look at how Hong Kong is faring,
边。 看看香港的情况，
because certainly there's going to be a lot of focus on tech.
因为肯定会有一个 非常注重技术。
But we have got more earnings coming through here coming soon.
但我们即将获得更多收入 很快就会经过这里。
And whether we continue to see his tech and how, you know, things were seen as a
我们是否继续看到他的技术 以及如何，你知道，事物被视为
little bit of a bright spot just given what we heard with open floor last week.
刚刚给出的一点亮点 上周我们在公开会议上听到的消息。
There has been some, of course, regulatory scrutiny.
当然，也有过一些， 监管审查。
But then again, the wider adoption of this whole technology, I think has been
但话又说回来，更广泛的采用 我认为这整个技术已经
you see in some of these big Internet giants and the like.
你在一些大型互联网中看到 巨人之类的。
So there you go. When it comes to show me, that could be
所以就这样吧。 当要向我展示时，这可能是
the big one here today. They just announced this launch of their
今天这里的大人物。 他们刚刚宣布推出他们的
new SUV. The stock is up one and a half percent.
新的SUV。 该股上涨了百分之一半。
We are seeing when it comes to dollar China, a bit of weakness here, but we've
我们看到当谈到美元时 中国，这里有点弱点，但我们已经
stabilised around the 690 level as well. It just tech is flat pretty much.
也稳定在690水平附近。 只是技术相当平坦。
You're not really seeing too much in terms of movement here.
你并没有真正看到太多 这里的运动条件。
Day We're pretty boring day, which you know is I don't it's rare to sort of
这一天我们很无聊，你 我知道我不知道这很少见
jinxed it. Well, let's take a listen to the oil
给它带来了厄运。 好吧，让我们听听油的声音
stocks here as well. Just given the fluctuations, a whipsaw
股票也在这里。 只是考虑到波动，洗盘
that we're seeing a little bit across crude markets here this morning.
我们看到了一点点 今天上午原油市场。
And we didn't see a whole lot really in terms of movement.
我们并没有真正看到很多 运动条件。
Mixed picture, as you can tell. Petro, China is up.
如您所知，混合图片。 中国石油上涨。
China oil services up. But, you know, Sinopec and the like are
中国石油服务上涨。 但是，你知道，中石化之类的公司
lot lower aluminum stocks that we talked about.
我们谈论的铝库存要低得多 关于。
So this could be the one where you start to see kind of the next phase of these
所以这可能是你开始的地方 看看这些的下一阶段
supply disruptions. As you are seeing, the likes of Choco
供应中断。 正如你所看到的，Choco之类的
Hong Kong are slightly lower here today. Aluminum futures are also still.
今天香港这里小幅走低。 铝期货也依旧。
Now we're coming off some of the highs here, but still that has been quite
现在我们正在走出一些高峰 在这里，但仍然相当
elevated of late. We do have those new home price data.
近来升高。 我们确实有这些新房价数据。
We do.
我们做到了。
And I think things just now are notching up of a level or two right now.
我认为现在的事情正在取得进展 现在上升一两个级别。
So let me start things off with so of two pieces of breaking news right now.
让我从以下开始吧 现在有两条突发新闻。
One is you have home prices coming out and the headline is we're looking at the
一是房价即将公布 标题是我们正在研究
slowest pace of declines, still declines.
下降速度仍然是最慢的 拒绝。
New home prices across 70 cities. That's per fib at the slowest pace going
70个城市的新建住宅价格。 这是每条纤维以最慢的速度进行的
back to June. So that's encouraging news as far as the
回到六月。 就目前而言，这是令人鼓舞的消息
direction of travel is concerned. The other piece of news, which is
行进方向有关。 另外一条新闻，就是
perhaps more pertinent globally, is the Dubai has now announced a temporary
也许在全球范围内更相关的是 迪拜现已宣布临时
suspension of flights at the international airport.
暂停航班 国际机场。
That goes back now to the to the Iran story.
这可以追溯到伊朗 故事。
It's unclear what has triggered that, but that's what we know so far.
目前尚不清楚是什么引发了这种情况 但这就是我们目前所知道的。
Go ahead, Yvonne. Just from what I'm seeing, the early get
继续吧，伊冯。 就我所见，早到
go. So not sure this is related, but there's
去。 所以不确定这是否相关，但有
something that's happened, the fire, the international airport.
发生的事情，火灾， 国际机场。
Yes. So the Dubai civil civil defense teams
是的。 所以迪拜民防队
have been containing a fire that was resulted from the impact of one of the
已经控制住了一场火灾 是由于其中之一的影响而产生的
two fuel tanks in the vicinity of the Dubai International Airport.
附近有两个油箱 迪拜国际机场。
This is according to the Dubai government's media office.
这是根据迪拜 政府媒体办公室。
And then they wrote this, an expose just a few moments ago.
然后他们写了这篇文章，揭露了 几分钟前。
No injuries have been reported so far. It appears to be a drone incident that
到目前为止，还没有人员受伤的报告。 这似乎是一起无人机事件
caused this fire near the airport and affected a fuel tank, according to the
在机场附近引发了这场火灾 据报道，影响了油箱
media office. So that might be impacting a lot of the
媒体办公室。 所以这可能会影响很多
traffic that is flying in and out of, of course, Dubai.
飞进和飞出的交通 当然是迪拜。
So for now, it's a temporary suspension of the airport.
所以目前暂时暂停 机场的。
Yeah, oil prices on your screens open above 1 to 4.
是的，屏幕上的油价已打开 以上1至4。
We're coming off. Well, we dip back below one, two, three.
我们要下车了 好吧，我们回到一、二、三以下。
And as you can see now, we are again inching our way back up on Brent Gold.
正如你现在所看到的，我们再次 布伦特金价缓慢回升。
Is below 5000. Yeah.
低于5000。 是的。
Now, we got not acting as a haven. That's a positioning play.
现在，我们不再充当避风港。 这就是定位打法。
Very quickly, NIKKEI Cosby, Taiwan and US futures coming on your screens.
很快，日经科斯比、台湾和 美国期货即将出现在您的屏幕上。
We're now down 1% on the Nikkei today. S&amp;P futures are the counterbalance to
今天日经指数下跌 1%。 标准普尔期货是平衡
the upside. Let's get a sense of what we know and
好的一面。 让我们了解一下我们所知道的和
how we can map out strategy if that is at all possible at this point.
如果是的话，我们如何制定战略 在这一点上完全有可能。
Make so Das is here with us on set Asia equity and quant strategist at Jp
让 Das 与我们一起出现在亚洲片场 Jp 股票和量化策略师
morgan. Good morning.
摩根。 早上好。
Very nice to see you, sir.
很高兴见到你，先生。
What scenarios have you mapped out and what strategies can you attach to those
您已经规划了哪些场景以及 你可以采取什么策略来应对这些
scenarios? There are so many permutations possible
场景？ 有很多排列的可能
at this point that investors are really struggling, right?
此时投资者确实 挣扎吧？
On the one hand, in the near-term, the situation is still ongoing.
一方面，从近期来看， 情况仍在持续。
So you should expect impacts on equities while for China, Right.
因此，您应该预期对股市的影响 而对于中国来说，对吧。
One is that risk aversion is happening and you can see positioning is being
一是避险情绪正在发生 你可以看到定位正在
degrowth a little bit, although not a lot so far.
稍微去生长，虽然不是 到目前为止很多。
Secondly, a variety of commodity prices that, like you guys were talking about
其次，各种商品价格 就像你们谈论的那样
have been going higher. And that affects both has winners and
一直在走高。 这会影响到赢家和
losers, right, both within sectors and within markets.
输家，对吧，无论是在行业内还是在 市场内。
Then you start to think about what's going to be the impact on inflation and
然后你开始思考什么是 将会对通货膨胀产生影响
how our central banks are going to react to this and how are bond yields going to
我们的央行将如何反应 对此以及债券收益率将如何
react to this. And that's starting to become a big
对此做出反应。 这开始成为一个大问题
story. You know, if you look at market
故事。 你知道，如果你看看市场
projections for policy moves from across central banks, we're now expecting more
对各地政策举措的预测 央行，我们现在期待更多
and more hikes. Right.
和更多的徒步旅行。 正确的。
And the final thing is, like you mentioned, you want what's going to
最后一件事是，像你一样 提到，你想要什么
happen about the Trump XI meeting, which is very critical to how risk perception
发生在特朗普十一届会议上 对于如何感知风险非常关键
is seen in China equities. So on the one hand, near-term, you
见于中国股市。 所以一方面，短期内，你
obviously want to be sensitive to these developments.
显然想要对这些敏感 事态发展。
And so the trend is to move from semis, semiconductors to semi, which is
所以趋势是从半决赛转向， 半导体到半半导体，即
staples, energy materials and industrials, all wondering where are you
主食、能源材料和 工业界，所有人都想知道你在哪里
going with that? Okay.
跟着那个？ 好的。
So that's that's a sector trade, which a lot of investors have been looking at.
这就是部门贸易， 很多投资者都在关注。
Similarly, you can use options to hedge. Jp morgan has just gone a tactically
同样，您可以使用期权来对冲。 摩根大通刚刚采取了战术行动
bullish on the dollar. So that's another way to look at it.
看涨美元。 这是另一种看待它的方式。
But longer term, the other option is to just look through these, Right.
但从长远来看，另一个选择是 看看这些，对吧。
History tells us, at least in the last 15 years, that geopolitical incidents
历史告诉我们，至少在过去 15年，地缘政治事件
have always been good buying opportunities, entry points for
一直很好买 机会、切入点
investors scaled back into their existing positions, ie stuff that they
投资者缩减投资规模 现有职位，即他们的东西
like. We're not quite there yet, but you know,
喜欢。 我们还没有完全做到这一点，但你知道，
you can just choose to look through this volatility.
你可以选择浏览这个 波动性。
Is it still the oil price that is really going to dictate how you position right
真的还是油价吗 将决定你如何正确定位
now? I mean, what does 100 hour oil mean for
现在？ 我的意思是，100小时油意味着什么
like investor psyches if it goes on for weeks and months?
就像投资者的心理一样，如果这种情况持续下去 几周和几个月？
Right. So three things to track, right?
正确的。 所以要跟踪三件事，对吗？
First is just the oil price. So if it stays above $100 for a month,
首先是石油价格。 所以如果一个月保持在100美元以上
that that starts to become a bigger economic challenge.
那开始变得更大 经济挑战。
Secondly, we're looking at indications that positions have been wiped out,
其次，我们正在寻找迹象 职位已被消灭，
which, like I said, we aren't seeing that yet.
正如我所说，我们没有看到 那还没有。
If you look at hedge funds positioning in our prime book, the de-growth thing
如果你看看对冲基金的定位 在我们的主要书中，去增长的事情
that we have seen so far is very minimal.
到目前为止我们所看到的非常 最小。
If you look at damage in the quant portfolios, in fact a performances,
如果你从数量上看伤害 作品集，实际上是表演，
that's very minimal. So we haven't seen that quite yet.
这是非常小的。 所以我们还没有看到这一点。
The third thing is to track like how are the these geopolitical events themselves
第三件事是跟踪如何 这些地缘政治事件本身
evolving? Right.
进化？ 正确的。
And I think the biggest focus from investors is on the Strait of Hormuz and
我认为最大的焦点来自 投资者位于霍尔木兹海峡
how soon that can reopen. And now we have betting markets odds on
多久可以重新开放。 现在我们的投注市场赔率
these things. So you can track that in real time.
这些事情。 这样您就可以实时跟踪。
Both option markets and betting markets are suggesting about a 35% probability
期权市场和博彩市场 建议大约 35% 的可能性
that the Strait of Hormuz will at least partially open by the end of the month.
霍尔木兹海峡至少 月底部分开放。
So we are tracking that very close. The if the war ended tomorrow, what has,
所以我们正在非常密切地追踪这一点。 如果战争明天结束，会发生什么，
let's call it, two and a half weeks, three weeks of elevated oil
就这样吧，两个半星期， 三周油价上涨
above 100 bucks. What is that?
100块以上。 那是什么？
Has there been fundamental damage done? Not yet.
是否已造成根本性损害？ 还没有。
So like I mentioned, I think either oil prices need to go up 150 or they need to
就像我提到的，我认为要么是石油 价格需要上涨 150，否则他们需要
stay at 100 for an extended period of time for the economic damage.
长时间保持在 100 造成经济损失的时间。
To the economic damage comes one way of positioning and then equity markets go
造成经济损失的一种方式是 定位，然后股市走向
down, bond markets perhaps sell off and you have a tightening in financial
下跌，债券市场可能会抛售 你的财政紧缩
conditions. So that leads to some damage.
状况。 所以这会导致一些损害。
Secondly, via central banks and how the policy direction is changing and that
其次，通过中央银行以及如何 政策方向正在发生变化
leads to some damage. Right.
导致一些损害。 正确的。
And the third thing is why is sentiment? So if you can get into a situation where
第三件事是为什么是情绪？ 所以如果你遇到这样的情况
you enter a downward spiral, where these things just feed off each other and then
你进入了一个螺旋式下降，其中这些 事物只是相互滋养，然后
the economy goes into a recession perhaps, or closer to a deeper downturn.
经济陷入衰退 也许，或者更接近更深的衰退。
But like I said, this is still very early stages in this.
但就像我说的，这仍然是非常 在此的早期阶段。
That's what you've also been talking about, how to position around the
这也是你一直在谈论的 关于，如何围绕
commodity sector. And one thing was I used to be just
商品部门。 有一件事是我曾经只是
overweight materials, but but is there a kind of a wider sort of trade now around
超重的材料，但是有没有一种 现在有一种更广泛的贸易
this? Yeah.
这？ 是的。
So this is a commodity. Is this something that we've like for a
所以这是一种商品。 这是我们喜欢的吗
while? Right like this Since the middle of last
尽管？ 就这样 从去年中期开始
year, we've been pushing commodity as an interesting space to be in.
今年，我们一直在推动商品作为 有趣的空间。
And that's not just because sort of a fragmenting world where, you know, macro
这不仅仅是因为 宏观世界支离破碎
traders will tell you to buy guns and gold like banks and tax what all of that
商人会告诉你买枪 黄金就像银行和税收什么的
leads to you to commodity exposure within materials.
导致您接触商品 材料内。
Then you start to think about, okay, everybody needs to have their secure
然后你开始思考，好吧， 每个人都需要有自己的安全
supply chain. And they will be over inventory, over
供应链。 他们的库存将会过剩，
hoarding. Everyone will try to secure their own
囤积。 每个人都会努力保护自己的安全
supplies of a variety of commodities. That's already happening.
供应各种商品。 这已经发生了。
So that drives commodity prices. Then you've got Andy Involution in
这推动了大宗商品价格的上涨。 那么你就得到了 Andy Involution
China, which is basically pushing down on supply, which has historically, at
中国，基本上是在压低 在供应方面，从历史上看，
least in the last ten years, been the biggest supply provider.
至少在过去十年中， 最大的供应商。
So you put all of these things together. And of course, from a financial
所以你把所有这些东西放在一起。 当然，从金融角度来说
perspective, if bonds are no longer diversifying your equity exposure as
观点认为，如果债券不再 使您的股票投资多元化
equity bond correlations go positive, which they have.
股票债券相关性呈正相关， 他们有。
Then the only thing that works is commodities.
那么唯一有效的就是 商品。
So all of these perspectives gives you a long commodity lens.
所以所有这些观点都给你一个 长商品镜头。
We have expressed that via various positions within Asian equities and even
我们已通过各种方式表示 亚洲股市的头寸，甚至
global equities. The way that seems more than tactical at
全球股票。 这种方式似乎不仅仅是战术上的
this point, you know, just the the the the wish to be more secure when it comes
这一点，你知道，只是 希望在到来时更加安全
to, I don't know, commodity security. What's the specific play there, though?
我不知道，商品安全。 那具体的玩法是什么呢？
Do I just buy upstream names to the infrastructure names?
我是否只购买上游名称 基础设施名称？
I think I think all of those so like the picks and shovels work, the you know,
我想我认为所有这些都非常喜欢 镐和铲子的工作，你知道，
the commodity producers work and everything in the mainstream.
商品生产者工作并 一切都在主流中。
Because once price hikes start to come through, it will follow through into
因为一旦价格开始上涨 通过，它将继续进入
midstream. And chemicals will also benefit from
中流。 化学品也将受益于
that over the long term. Right.
从长远来看。 正确的。
Because these price increases typically tend to cascade across the entire supply
因为这些价格通常会上涨 往往会级联到整个供应链
chain. So if the initial benefits will be in
链。 所以如果最初的好处是
the upstream players, but then that will kind of cascade.
上游玩家，但那样就会 一种级联。
Keep in mind, energy as a sector used to be like 20% of GM back in 2007 when I
请记住，能源作为一个行业过去 就像 2007 年 20% 的通用汽车公司员工一样
started. Now it's like 3%.
开始了。 现在大概是3%。
So there has been a significant change in the way that the market processes
所以发生了重大的变化 以市场处理的方式
things and how the economies have evolved.
事情以及经济如何 进化了。
But there was a time when energy used to be a very big sector.
但曾经有一段时间，能源被用来 是一个非常大的部门。
You mentioned you're still seeing this kind of wall liquidity for even this
你提到你仍然看到这个 即使是这样的墙壁流动性
year. You still think that that's happening.
年。 你仍然认为那件事正在发生。
Are we seeing any early signs of that now?
我们是否看到了任何早期迹象？ 现在？
So like I said, there's a lot of confusion, a lot of permutations
所以就像我说的，有很多 混乱，很多排列
possible right now. So there is a scenario where the global
现在可能。 所以有一个场景，全球
economy goes into a recession, then there's no liquidity.
经济陷入衰退，然后 没有流动性。
Yeah, there's a scenario where our tactical dollar bullishness becomes more
是的，有一个场景，我们的 美元战术看多变得更加明显
permanent, then there's not a lot of liquidity.
永久的，那么就没有很多 流动性。
But to the extent that, yes, global portfolios want to diversify out of
但在某种程度上，是的，全球 投资组合希望多元化
their very heavily concentrated positions, which have traditionally been
他们非常集中 传统上的职位
in tech in the U.S. and into emerging markets, as earnings
在美国从事科技行业 并进入新兴市场，因为收益
growth becomes better, that's still out there.
增长变得更好，但仍然存在 那里。
Similarly, for emerging market money, for household money in Asia, in other
同样，对于新兴市场货币来说， 亚洲家庭的钱，其他国家的家庭钱
emerging markets, diversifying by bringing it back into the local markets,
新兴市场，多元化 将其带回当地市场，
it's a big thing in several markets in our part of the world.
这在多个市场都是一件大事 我们的世界。
So all of these things are still happening.
所以所有这些事情仍然 正在发生。
But yes, in a recession, in a dollar strong environment, the world doesn't
但是，是的，在经济衰退时，以美元计算 强大的环境，世界上没有
happen. It becomes more of a trickle.
发生。 它变得更像是涓涓细流。
We have a flurry of central bank decisions this week, I think at the G7
我们有一系列央行 我认为七国集团本周将作出决定
plus a few more. Any risk to watch out for there?
再加上一些。 那里有什么需要注意的风险吗？
And as far as how they're looking at what's going on, whether there's
就他们的看法而言 发生了什么事，是否有
something semi-permanent to liquidity to your point.
半永久性的流动性 你的观点。
But that's exactly what we'll be looking out for.
但这正是我们要寻找的 出去。
So especially with the FOMC, we'll see. Of course, this is Chair Paul, those
因此，特别是对于联邦公开市场委员会（FOMC），我们拭目以待。 当然，这是保罗主席，那些
final few FOMC. So maybe you cannot take a lot of
最后几个FOMC。 所以也许你不能带很多
signalling information about future policy direction from this.
有关未来的信号信息 政策方向由此而来。
But of course, the way that the committee thinks about it will be
但当然， 委员会认为这将是
important for investors to follow in terms of how whether they are looking
对于投资者来说重要的是要跟进 他们看起来如何
through this as a transitory I hate to use that word, but transitory bout of
我讨厌通过这短暂的经历 使用这个词，但短暂的发作
inflation or whether they see this as, you know, causing more lasting damage to
通货膨胀或者他们是否认为这是， 你知道，造成更持久的损害
inflation expectations, which have also started to move.
通胀预期也 开始移动。
So that's a debate that we'll be listening out more for.
这就是我们将要进行的辩论 多听听。
Secondly, an emerging market central bank, Brazil.
其次，新兴市场中心 银行，巴西。
It meets later this week and we'll see whether they deliver cuts because
它将于本周晚些时候召开，我们拭目以待 他们是否削减开支是因为
they're expected to. And that will give us some additional
他们预计会。 这会给我们一些额外的
insight on how emerging markets are thinking about this whole episode.
对新兴市场现状的洞察 思考整个情节。
How do you look at China now? I mean, there's a growing narrative that
您现在如何看待中国？ 我的意思是，越来越多的叙述是
they're insulated from all the Iran situation.
他们与所有伊朗人隔绝 情况。
Are Chinese assets more attractive to you now?
中国资产是否更具吸引力 你现在呢？
Yeah, We've been looking at China as having emerged from a four year down
是的，我们一直把中国视为 走出四年的低谷
cycle or fundamental down cycle from 2020 to 2024.
周期或基本下行周期 2020 年至 2024 年。
And then we've started to see that recovery and we have more confidence
然后我们开始看到 复苏，我们更有信心
that this recovery is real. Just looking at what's happening on the
这种复苏是真实的。 只是看看发生了什么
innovation side, what's happening on the geopolitical side, what's happening on
创新方面，正在发生的事情 地缘政治方面，正在发生的事情
that involution side, what's happening in terms of policy support for
内卷方面，发生了什么 在政策支持方面
consumption, for property. And you just saw the property market
消费，为了财产。 而你刚刚看到了房地产市场
data. All of these are pointing in a direction
数据。 所有这些都指向一个方向
that's fundamentally positive for the market.
这对于 市场。
A lot of the issues in China have been that many foreign investors have become
中国的很多问题都已经解决了 许多外国投资者已经成为
a little bit risk averse in China because of the geopolitical issues.
在中国有点规避风险 因为地缘政治问题。
And we don't really need to see that money coming into China just yet.
我们真的不需要看到这一点 资金还没有进入中国。
I think the first leg votes, that's a bonus.
我认为第一回合的投票是 奖金。
Yeah. But the first leg higher in China could
是的。 但中国首轮走高可能
be simply the domestic money getting deployed into the market.
只是国内的钱得到 部署到市场。
We started to see retail investors buying equities from September last
我们开始看到散户投资者 去年9月份开始买股票
year. And there's a lot.
年。 而且有很多。
More of that to go in. Households in China have been putting
还有更多的内容要进去。 中国家庭已经把
increasingly more of their wealth into deposit bank deposits in the last few
他们越来越多的财富 最近几年银行存款
years. And if that even a small part of that
年。 如果那只是其中的一小部分
moves into the equity market, that's like $300 billion of inflows into
进入股市，那就是 比如3000亿美元的资金流入
Chinese equities. Nikko, it's great to have you, Mr.
中国股票。 Nikko，很高兴有你，先生。
Das there, Asian equity and quant strategist at J.P.
那里，亚洲股票和量化 J.P. 策略师
Morgan. I just want to recap the you know, when
摩根. 我只是想回顾一下你知道的
it came to the data. Yes.
它涉及到数据。 是的。
The home price drop that we saw in China was at a slower pace.
我们在中国看到的房价下跌 速度较慢。
That is certainly a bright spot, as I mentioned.
这当然是一个亮点，因为我 提到的。
Then there's a situation with the Dubai International Airport where we have
还有迪拜的情况 我们所在的国际机场
heard the government that they have temporarily suspended flights at the
听说政府他们有 暂时停飞航班
international airport. According to the government's media
国际机场。 据政府媒体报道
center, there has been a fire impacting a fuel tank near the international
中心发生火灾，影响 国际附近的一个油箱
airport. So certainly we are watching the
飞机场。 所以我们当然正在观看
airlines very closely. They are getting a negative reaction to
航空公司关系非常密切。 他们收到负面反应
all of this as well. Keep in mind, Dubai is one of the
所有这一切也是如此。 请记住，迪拜是
world's, if not the one of the world's, the world's busiest sort of travel hubs
世界的，即使不是世界的， 世界上最繁忙的旅游中心
as well. So certainly temporarily, even a
以及。 所以肯定是暂时的，即使是
temporary suspension could have massive, massive implications here.
临时暂停可能会产生巨大的影响， 这里有巨大的影响。
So certainly one to watch. It is ongoing situation.
所以肯定值得一看。 这是持续的情况。
We'll give you an update once we hear more about this drone incident near the
一旦我们听到消息，我们就会向您提供最新消息 有关这起无人机事件的更多信息
Dubai International Airport. This is Bloomberg.
迪拜国际机场。 这是布隆伯格。
Right. Welcome back.
正确的。 欢迎回来。
So South Korea will use extra tax revenue to fund a supplementary budget
所以韩国会征收额外税 为补充预算提供资金的收入
in a bid really to cushion consumers and businesses from rising oil prices
为了真正缓冲消费者和 企业免受油价上涨影响
because of what's happening in Iran and in the Middle East.
因为伊朗发生的事情以及 在中东。
Its finance minister spoke with us exclusively on Friday.
其财政部长与我们交谈 仅限周五。
Two among the to go target to corroborate that can get to them by the
其中两个目标是 证实可以通过
right. Right now the Middle East situation is
正确的。 目前中东局势
overshadowing the global economy. The government's top priority right now
给全球经济蒙上阴影。 政府当前的首要任务
is responding to the Middle East situation in the short term, while
正在回应中东 短期内的情况，同时
reducing Korea's structural dependence on oil over the medium to long term.
减少韩国的结构性依赖 中长期来看石油。
Some of that, I guess, which is why you just announced a fuel price cap.
我想，其中一些，这就是为什么你 刚刚宣布了燃油价格上限。
Why this specific measure instead of others more potentially broadly or more
为什么采取这一具体措施而不是 其他更广泛或更广泛的潜力
targeted measures to support the economy, to hunger?
有针对性的支持措施 经济，挨饿？
Isn't it? Currently the imported oil is from
不是吗？ 目前进口石油来自
before the Middle East conflict. During this two week period when imports
中东冲突之前。 在进口的这两周期间
have been halted, they will come in at a higher price.
已被停止，他们将在 价格更高。
However, if the future imports become even more expensive, the government
然而，如果未来的进口量变成 更贵的是政府
plans to raise the price proposal accordingly to compensate.
计划提高价格建议 相应地进行补偿。
The government plans to decide at that time whether to reduce taxes again, cut
政府计划届时做出决定 时间是否再次减税、削减
their spending on health care. What is the middle?
他们在医疗保健上的支出。 中间是什么？
If you actually need to help the refiners?
如果您确实需要帮助 炼油厂？
Does that mean that the government will be using its own budget in order to do
这是否意味着政府将 使用自己的预算来做
that? And how are you planning to pay for that
那？ 您打算如何支付费用
cost? Chris So my nugget is quite so.
成本？ 克里斯 所以我的金块就是这样。
Therefore, if refiners incur losses during this process, the government
因此，如果炼油厂蒙受损失 在此过程中，政府
intends to compensate for those losses. Would that come from the extra budget?
打算补偿这些损失。 这来自额外的预算吗？
Chris, I tell you that if crude, although we also have plans to prepare
克里斯，我告诉你，如果粗鲁的话， 虽然我们也有计划准备
an additional supplementary budget if necessary, and in fact the government
额外的补充预算，如果 必要的，事实上政府
has already begun working on this internally.
已经开始着手这方面的工作 内部。
So therefore, it's not just about compensating for the proposed oil price
因此，这不仅仅是关于 补偿拟议的油价
increase. The government has begun preparing a
增加。 政府已经开始准备
supplementary budget to support those suffering losses due to rising oil
补充预算以支持这些 因油价上涨而蒙受损失
prices. Our freight transporters, delivery
价格。 我们的货运商、送货
service providers exporting SMEs, small and medium sized companies, the
出口中小型企业的服务提供商 和中型企业，
self-employed, small business owners and young people tend
自营职业者、小企业主和 年轻人倾向于
to come out sympathetic. There's so much skepticism right now,
表现出同情心。 现在有很多质疑
though, in the markets. I mean, we have seen the incredible
不过，在市场上。 我的意思是，我们已经看到了令人难以置信的
rally of the Korean stock market just to fall incredibly earlier this month as
韩国股市的反弹只是为了 本月早些时候的跌幅令人难以置信
well. Not to mention the pressure on the
出色地。 更不用说所承受的压力
Korean one. What more can the government do to them?
韩国的一个。 政府还能对他们做什么？
Korean. One is the trading improving on the
韩国人。 一是交易改善
one's recent weakness is not due to shortage of dollars.
一个人最近的虚弱并不是因为 美元短缺。
Korea holds over 1 trillion in combined dollar assets, including roughly 500
韩国总共持有超过1万亿美元 美元资产，包括大约 500
billion at the National Pension Service, more than 420 billion in state reserves
国民年金公团的 100 亿美元， 国家储备超过4200亿
and over 100 billion in private holdings.
以及超过1000亿的私人资金 持股。
The recent depreciation has largely reflected Middle East related
最近的贬值在很大程度上 反映中东相关
developments. While last year's movements were
事态发展。 虽然去年的走势是
influenced by increasing outbound investments by residents.
受出境人数增加影响 居民投资。
This year, the current account surplus is expected to improve further on the
今年经常项目顺差 预计将进一步改善
back of the semiconductor boom. Secondly, w GBA inclusion could bring
半导体繁荣的背后。 其次，融入大湾区可以带来
additional foreign inflows into the bond market and the pensions new hedging
额外的外资流入该债券 市场和养老金新对冲
framework could enhance dollar stability.
框架可以提振美元 稳定性。
The rally that we have seen recently and that reflected the economic fundamentals
我们最近看到的反弹 反映了经济基本面
of South Korea and how much is its speculative herd behavior together with
韩国的价格是多少 投机性羊群行为
effects, together with the Korean stock market?
以及韩国股市的影响 市场？
And is that a risk to hang stomach some it hanging on?
这是一个悬而未决的风险吗？ 它挂在吗？
Is it tomorrow money or less? The stock market's recent drop of over
明天是钱还是更少？ 近期股市跌幅超过
700 points valuing Middle East tensions is seen as part of a normalization
700分评价中东紧张局势 被视为正常化的一部分
process. After strong gains, it is not viewed as
过程。 在强劲上涨之后，它不被视为
a drastic sell off. We are closely monitoring volatility in
大幅抛售。 我们正在密切关注波动性
the foreign exchange and bond markets and stand ready to take policy measures
外汇和债券市场 并准备采取政策措施
if necessary to stabilize conditions. The uncertainty coming from the trade
如果有必要稳定条件。 贸易带来的不确定性
environment. Again, we're hearing from the US trade
环境。 我们再次听到美国贸易界的消息
representative, a 301. Section probes into alleged excess
代表，a 301。 部门调查涉嫌超额行为
manufacturing capacity. Have you spoken to Washington about that
制造能力。 你和华盛顿谈过这件事吗
already? More than most Washington.
已经？ 比大多数华盛顿人还要多。
I heard you again, not to mention to, although we have not had recent
我又听到你了，更不用说， 虽然我们最近没有
discussions with Washington, the U.S. side has reacted very positively to
与美国华盛顿的讨论 双方反应非常积极
Korea's passage yesterday of the special bill related to U.S.
韩国昨天通过的特别 与美国相关的法案
investment. The overall response from Washington has
投资。 华盛顿方面的总体反应是
been very favorable. Now that the legislation has passed,
非常有利。 既然立法已经通过了，
specific investment projects will likely be determined through working level
具体投资项目可能会 根据工作水平确定
consultations. The U.S.
磋商。 美国
has shown strong interest in the energy sector in particular, and Korea believes
对能源表现出了浓厚的兴趣 尤其是该行业，韩国认为
it has competitive strengths in that area.
它在这方面具有竞争优势 区。
We intend to pursue mutually beneficial cooperation that will be good for both
我们旨在追求互惠互利 合作对双方都有利
Korea and the U.S. could among our habit of hello have
韩国和美国 我们打招呼的习惯中可以有
another. When it comes to the Supreme Court
其他。 当涉及到最高法院时
actually striking down many of President Trump's tariffs for Korean Korean
实际上推翻了许多总统 特朗普对韩国人征收关税
companies. Is that an opportunity or does just
公司。 这是一个机会还是只是
create more uncertainty around trade to come in the middle of the table?
给贸易带来更多不确定性 来到桌子中间？
One is regarding tariffs. If the U.S.
一是关于关税。 如果美国
Supreme Court's decision invalidates the 15% reciprocal tariff while maintaining
最高法院的判决宣告无效 15%的互惠关税，同时维持
10%, Korea, having already reached a 15% agreement, does not expect higher rates
10%，韩国已经达到15% 协议，预计不会有更高的利率
than previously agreed. One, Section three or one actions
比之前约定的。 一、第三节或一动作
affecting surplus countries, including Korea and Japan.
影响盈余国家，包括 韩国和日本。
The government will actively engage and explain its position.
政府将积极参与并 解释其立场。
Right. I just don't look at markets.
正确的。 我只是不看市场。
A couple of things. Right.
有几件事。 正确的。
So this update coming through out of the Dubai International Airport and we're
所以这个更新来自 迪拜国际机场，我们
now at about session highs, 104 on Brent, still above 100, I think is the
现在大约是盘中高点，104 布伦特原油，仍高于 100，我认为是
key takeaway there. Home prices came out out of China 30
那里的关键要点。 中国房价走出30
minutes back, the slowest pace of declines going back to June.
分钟前，最慢的节奏 下降趋势可以追溯到六月。
That's helping things along. We're showing a SGB curve at the moment.
这对事情的发展很有帮助。 我们目前显示的是 SGB 曲线。
Steepening their property prices are also doing quite well in the next hour.
房地产价格陡峭 在接下来的一个小时里也表现得很好。
Two things the data dump and Indonesia comes online following that massive drop
数据转储和印度尼西亚的两件事 在大幅下降后上线
on Friday. All things are just ahead.
在周五。 一切都在前方。
Lots more on the way here on the China show.
还有更多的事情正在中国的路上 显示。
Live pictures out of Beijing here this morning.
北京外景现场照片在这里 早上。
The State Council information office set to have its press briefing as we await,
国务院新闻办公厅集 在我们等待期间举行新闻发布会，
of course, for this January and February activity data out of China.
当然，今年一月和二月 中国以外的活动数据。
Here in the meantime, we are seeing when it comes to stocks are slightly on offer
与此同时，我们看到什么时候 谈到股票略有优惠
here today. CSI 300 is lower by about 6/10 of 1%.
今天就在这里。 沪深300指数下跌约1%的6/10。
There is a lot of headlines here when it comes to the Iran situation.
当它出现时，这里有很多头条新闻 说到伊朗局势。
No surprise. You know, first it was really the likes
毫不奇怪。 你知道，首先是真正的喜欢
of this U.S. attack on this Iranian export hub.
这个美国的 对这个伊朗出口中心的袭击。
Then you have this kind of more talk from President Trump about, you know,
然后你还有这样的谈话 特朗普总统关于，你知道，
reopening the Strait of Hormuz and trying to get China and other nations to
重新开放霍尔木兹海峡 试图让中国和其他国家
help out in that regard. So certainly there's a lot of that.
在这方面提供帮助。 所以肯定有很多这样的事情。
And then, of course, there's Dubai International Airport temporarily
当然，还有迪拜 暂时国际机场
suspending flights there. That certainly has again, led people to
暂停那里的航班。 这无疑再次导致人们
a bit more concern about what's really going on on the ground.
多关心一下真实情况 地面上正在发生的事情。
Following that drone drone related strike and, of course, a fire that,
继无人机无人机相关 罢工，当然还有火灾，
okay, we're now getting the numbers coming through, activity numbers.
好的，我们现在正在获取数字 即将到来，活动数量。
Okay. So we're looking at retail sales, 2.8%
好的。 所以我们关注的是零售额，2.8%
above estimates, industrial production, 6.3%.
以上估计，工业生产， 6.3%。
Estimates were for 5.3%. What else are you seeing?
估计为5.3%。 你还看到什么？
Everybody. So it seems like it's a bit across the
大家。 所以看起来有点跨越了
board at first glance. Right.
乍一看板。 正确的。
So industrial production at 6.3. Fixed asset investment actually is in
因此工业生产率为 6.3。 固定资产投资实际在
positive territory. We're talking about 1.8% print.
积极的领土。 我们谈论的是 1.8% 的印刷品。
We were expecting a -5% print or more. And then property investment also is
我们预计打印量为 -5% 或更多。 然后房地产投资也是
better than expected still in contraction, but we're talking about
仍好于预期 收缩，但我们正在谈论
11.1% decline. So it seems better than expected.
下降11.1%。 所以看起来比预想的要好。
And this really kind of you pair that with the home price data that we got
这真的很适合你们 根据我们得到的房价数据
just about 30 minutes ago, where the declines seem to moderate it a bit, I
就在大约 30 分钟前， 下降似乎有点缓和，我
think things are pointing at a more positive direction here right now, Dave.
认为事情指向更多 现在这里有积极的方向，戴夫。
Yeah, it's you're right. I mean, this is an across the board beat
是的，你说得对。 我的意思是，这是一个全面的节拍
on I think I would even say all with the exception I guess of the jobless rate
我想我什至会说所有 我猜测失业率是个例外
which actually ticked higher to 5.3% from 5.1%.
实际上上涨至 5.3% 从 5.1% 起。
But most activity numbers are suggesting there was a lot more economic activity
但大多数活动数据都表明 有更多的经济活动
for the period between Jan to Fed and to Evans points, In case you missed that,
一月至美联储至 埃文斯指出，如果你错过了这一点，
the home price numbers for Fed which came out 30 minutes back, also coming in
美联储的房价数据 30分钟前出来，也进来了
less bad than expected the slowest pace of the clients and new home prices going
没有预期的那么糟糕，速度最慢 客户数量和新房价格走势
back to about June of last year. Let's get some more analysis now on
时间回到去年六月左右。 现在让我们进行更多分析
bring in Ning Jang, senior China economist at UBS Investment Bank.
引进中国资深人士Ning Jang 瑞银投资银行经济学家。
Seems like a pretty good set of numbers. What's your take on them?
看起来是一组相当不错的数字。 你对他们有何看法？
Sure. There are three takeaways from here.
当然。 这里有三个要点。
Number one, of course, there is a better than expected activity data in January,
第一，当然还有更好的 一月份的活动数据好于预期，
February across the board. Number two, the still notable divergence
二月全面。 第二，差异仍然显着
between external demand from exports versus kind of a still soft domestic
外部需求与出口之间 与仍然疲软的国内相比
activities. Number three, when you do double check
活动。 第三，当你仔细检查时
the data very carefully because there's a notable disruption from the
数据非常仔细，因为有 的显着干扰
transition, how they basically fact even last year we have some disruption in
过渡，他们基本上是如何做到的 去年我们遇到了一些干扰
fact as have the. Okay.
事实上就已经了。 好的。
That's okay. So I know you've only had the benefit of
没关系。 所以我知道你只得到了以下好处
hearing us give you the headline numbers.
听我们给您介绍标题 数字。
You know, when you look at what specific details are you curious to see now, now
你知道，当你看看具体的内容时 您现在想看细节吗？
that you have a headline number that suggests things are better?
您的标题数字是 表明事情变得更好了？
Yes. Sure.
是的。 当然。
So basically we're seeing two or three since the first one.
所以基本上我们看到两三个 从第一个开始。
So whether this kind of a consumption uptick in January-February can be
那么这种消费是否 1-2月份可能会有所回升
extended even for the French speaking or speak in China, consumption should be
甚至适用于讲法语的人或 在中国讲，消费应该是
still under pressure. We're looking at some smaller cereal
仍然面临压力。 我们正在寻找一些较小的谷物
subsidies and no much increase on the social spending.
补贴并没有大幅增加 社会支出。
And also the house housing price was, in fact, still negative.
还有房价，在 事实上，仍然是消极的。
So that's why we're still some pressure here.
所以这就是为什么我们仍然有一些压力 在这里。
So that could start in this year, in the end of February, but give up a little
因此，这可以从今年开始，在 二月底，但放弃一点
bit of more confidence. But clearly, we need more.
多一点信心。 但显然，我们需要更多。
So that first one second one is if I had data.
所以第一个第二个是如果我有 数据。
Last year was almost a 4% decline. And in this year we have almost a 2%
去年下降了近4%。 今年我们有近 2%
increase. So that's a lot of the questions over
增加。 所以很多问题就这样结束了
the year, especially on the base effect last year.
年份，尤其是基数效应 去年。
I see. So do you think there is enough momentum
我懂了。 那么你认为动力够吗
in terms of the fixed asset investment now that we've turned positive?
从固定资产投资来看 现在我们已经变得积极了吗？
Is there a sustainability in these and what's driving it, do you think?
这些是否具有可持续性？ 您认为是什么在推动它？
Is it mostly, just as you say, base effects or is it could be more?
是不是像你说的那样，基本 效果还是可以更多？
So last year, while we saw a notable decline in second half of last year,
所以去年，虽然我们看到了一个值得注意的 去年下半年有所下降，
three things. Number one, that's kind of a kitchen
三件事。 第一，那是厨房
sink. Some some base was brought down to
下沉。 一些基地被降级为
ensure a decent growth in this year in some local governments.
确保今年经济平稳增长 一些地方政府。
Now to here some projects are being delayed to this year to enjoy the fresh
现在有些项目正在进行中 推迟到今年才能享受新鲜
kind of support from a new five year plan.
新五年的支持 计划。
Number three, some funding gap was there last year, though.
第三，存在一些资金缺口 不过去年。
Governments try to still pay our bills and that yielding some funding for
政府仍然试图支付我们的账单 并为
projects. So clearly, maybe some kind of
项目。 很明显，也许某种
disruption. This has been normalized.
扰乱。 这已经正常化了。
So that's a good news for the data. But clearly the Algren evidence, those
所以这对数据来说是个好消息。 但显然，阿尔格伦的证据，那些
maybe is a chance is not a dramatic. We have some disruption from the.
也许是一个机会而不是一个戏剧性的。 我们受到了一些干扰。
Fact and statistics. You you mentioned something just now,
事实和统计数据。 你刚才提到了一些事情，
too. You said more was needed.
也。 你说还需要更多。
More economic support is needed because the when you talk about the consumer,
需要更多的经济支持，因为 当你谈论消费者时
for example, the you know one of the early reads, so they reduce the amount
例如，您知道其中之一 早期阅读，因此他们减少了数量
of consumer subsidies. Right.
的消费补贴。 正确的。
And I think one of the first data points that came out following that news was
我认为第一个数据点 该消息发布后
the monthly car sales numbers and bit on the softer side and should be over.
每月汽车销量数据及相关信息 较软的一面应该结束。
Think that or is there has there been an effect really on consumer spending
认为或是否有过 对消费者支出的实际影响
because of less support? The bottom line here, January, February,
因为支持较少？ 最重要的是，一月、二月，
the retail sales is still below 3%. Last year was close to 4%, which means
零售额仍低于3%。 去年接近4%，这意味着
we're still seeing a deceleration of consumption data in China this year.
我们仍然看到减速 今年中国的消费数据。
So if you say is a positive, I hear it is some time, which means even the
所以如果你说的是积极的，我听到了 是一段时间，这意味着即使
government to try to support a growth in the longer run to push up the share of
政府试图支持经济增长 从长远来看会推高份额
consumption in GDP, notably. But clearly in this year, the initial
尤其是消费占 GDP 的比重。 但显然在今年，最初
boost looks modest. Maybe it will still need a strong
提升看起来不大。 或许还需要强大的力量
increasing spending on social safety net.
增加社会保障支出 净。
And also we need to wait for the final stabilization of the housing prices,
而且我们还需要等待最终的结果 房价稳定，
plus the meaningful push income growth in China.
加上有意义的推动收入增长 在中国。
You mentioned about the stabilization of the home price.
您提到了稳定化 房价。
We're starting to see the declines moderate.
我们开始看到下降 中等。
Is do you think there are some signs of some sort of bottom that's being formed
你是否认为有一些迹象 正在形成某种底部
here for China as a whole?
这里 对于整个中国来说？
Our average maybe we still need another couple of quarters to see the
我们的平均水平也许我们还需要另一个 几个季度来看
stabilization across two different tier cities.
两个不同层级的稳定性 城市。
But a good ASEAN's in the very beginning, lesser averages, maybe high
但一个好的东盟 开始，平均值较低，可能较高
tier cities like Shanghai, maybe Shenzhen, Beijing could enjoy the first,
可能是上海这样的一线城市 深圳、北京可享受第一，
a sign of stabilization, which could be a leading indicator for the lower tier
稳定的迹象，这可能是 下层的领先指标
cities. So that's what's happening now.
城市。 这就是现在正在发生的事情。
As you can see, the secondary home sales in Shanghai boomed in the past several
正如你所看到的，二手房销售 近几年在上海蓬勃发展
weeks. Yeah, I was about to ask you, do you
几周。 是的，我正想问你，你呢？
think we're past we're way past the worst in the first tier cities as a
认为我们已经过去了，我们已经过去了 一线城市最差
leading indicator to the broader economy.
更广泛的领先指标 经济。
If, say, the second year of say yes, maybe we have already passed the worst,
如果说，第二年说“是”， 也许最坏的时候我们已经过去了
but in terms of the direction ought to be saying we still need to be a little
但就方向而言应该 是说我们还需要一点
bit more patient. You know, every time we saw a boost on
更有耐心一点。 你知道，每次我们看到增长
the home market, it probably was eating. It has a honeymoon, which means no
国内市场，它可能正在吃饭。 它有蜜月期，这意味着没有
honeymoon. What's next?
蜜月。 接下来怎么办？
So that's a more important question for me.
所以这是一个更重要的问题 我。
I'm getting a lot of questions about the Iran conflict depending on the duration
我收到很多关于 伊朗冲突取决于持续时间
and intensity. But could it do anything in terms of
和强度。 但它能做些什么吗
impacting the global demand for exports, which China has benefited from?
影响全球出口需求， 中国从中受益了哪些？
It depends the scenario we are assuming now, clearly the market has not yet
这取决于我们假设的场景 现在，显然市场还没有
pristine a prolonged shock from the elevated price, which means everyone is
原始的长期震惊 价格上涨，这意味着每个人都
looking at it maybe for the last couple of weeks, still in chaos and elevated
看看它也许是最后一对 几周来，仍然处于混乱和升高状态
oil prices, but after that maybe get back to normal.
石油价格，但之后可能会得到 恢复正常。
So that's a scenario where assuming now. So if the oil prices stayed out of it
这就是现在假设的情况。 所以如果油价不受影响的话
for months, clearly that's a risk of some kind of a small mini a global
几个月来，显然这是一个风险 某种小型迷你全球
recession scenario upcoming. That's it will be negative news for
经济衰退情景即将到来。 这将是负面消息
China. But for China per say, China looks more
中国。 但对于中国来说，中国看起来更多
resilient, made as a global oil shock because of the high oil reserves,
具有弹性，因全球石油危机而产生 由于石油储量高，
because of the small dependency on oil in the in the total energy consumption.
由于对石油的依赖程度较低 在能源消耗总量中。
And also China has a very special scheme in managing the domestic gasoline
而且中国还有一个非常特别的计划 在管理国内汽油方面
prices. How does that affect people in China,
价格。 这对中国人有什么影响
this global rally and commodity prices agnostic of wait there.
全球反弹和大宗商品价格 不知道在那里等待。
Let's set aside why they're rallying. Does that help China
让我们先把他们集会的原因放在一边。 这对中国有帮助吗
for the the pie? That's for sure.
为了馅饼？ 这是肯定的。
We already saw a meaningful uptick in the past two months ahead of the before
我们已经看到了显着的上升 比之前提前两个月
this kind of global oil shock pie turned the last negative to -0.9% with our
这种全球石油冲击的馅饼变了 最后的负数为-0.9%
price uptake in March, which we can see may turn positive each year in the two
3月份的价格上涨，我们可以看到 每年都可能转正
or three months. So that's good news for Thailand
或三个月。 这对泰国来说是个好消息
reading. But clearly that's another challenge for
阅读。 但显然这是另一个挑战
military industrial sectors. That's the increased cost, right?
军事工业部门。 这就是增加的成本吧？
That's a negative news for margin and their profitability.
这对利润率来说是一个负面消息 他们的盈利能力。
It seems like an NPC, they said a pretty strong vow to to get inflation back to
看起来像个NPC，他们说很漂亮 强烈誓言要让通货膨胀恢复到
2%. How do you think that what I get there,
2%。 你觉得我得到的东西怎么样
unfortunately for this year, the CPI target of 2% is not a binding one and
不幸的是，今年的CPI 2% 的目标不是一个具有约束力的目标，并且
our baseline still assume a 0.6% CPI for this year better than last year, 0%, but
我们的基线仍然假设 CPI 为 0.6% 今年比去年好，0%，但是
still well below the 2% CPI target. And that's because we're strongly
仍远低于2%的CPI目标。 那是因为我们强烈
needing the decent boost and consumption and also kind of income growth getting
需要适当的刺激和消费 以及收入增长的方式
back. But so far, maybe that's still very
后退。 但到目前为止，也许这仍然是非常
modest. I wonder if you've seen the the
谦虚的。 我想知道你是否看过
steepening in the curve recently. Why do you think?
最近曲线变陡。 你认为为什么？
Well, if you've seen it, why do you think we've seen a steepening there
好吧，如果你已经看到了，为什么你 我认为我们已经看到了那里的陡峭
for the near term one? I mean, the short term tenor, is there
近期？ 我的意思是，短期的趋势是存在的
still some expectations for PBOC cut interest rate, which will be directly
央行降息仍有一定预期 利率，将直接
linked with a short term tenor, But for the long term tenor, like ten year, 30
与短期期限相关，但对于 长期期限，例如十年、30
years, inflation expectations are coming back that are pushing are but some kind
年，通胀预期即将来临 正在推动的背部只是某种
of a no no a nominal reading of the long term trend of their rate.
的 否 否 长的标称读数 他们的利率的长期趋势。
That's why the ZB yield curve getting steeper.
这就是为什么 ZB 收益率曲线变得 更陡。
So that's what's happening now. A couple of weeks there could be a
这就是现在正在发生的事情。 几周后可能会有
meeting potentially between President Trump and she.
总统之间可能会面 特朗普和她。
Obviously, the Iran situation is somehow being thrown into it, whether it happens
显然，伊朗的局势在某种程度上 被扔进去，无论它发生
or not. But what are your base case assumptions?
或不。 但您的基本情况假设是什么？
Should we expect the truce that was set in South Korea last year just to be
我们是否应该期待已定的休战 去年在韩国只是为了
maintained or do you think something more could come through?
维持或你认为什么 还能有更多的事情发生吗？
There are two streams here. One is the top kind of a talk in Paris
这里有两条溪流。 一种是巴黎最顶级的演讲
now between the Holy Father and peasant. So is there still on the ground work to
现在在教宗和农民之间。 那么，还有哪些基础工作要做呢？
prepare for this upcoming potential meeting of the triumvirate in China?
为即将到来的潜力做好准备 三巨头在中国开会？
The other one for sure. Trump send a message that the US needs
另一个肯定是。 特朗普发出了美国需要的信息
China help to get the hammer straight back to normal.
中国帮助解决问题 恢复正常。
So that's a lever I believe is still uncertain whether Trump could make it a
所以我相信这仍然是一个杠杆 不确定特朗普能否使其成为
trip or not. We could see a very kind of a
旅行与否。 我们可以看到一种非常
slate of messages in the next couple of days, hopefully.
接下来的消息列表 天，希望如此。
But our baseline, of course, even though there's a trade war or not, is there is
但当然，我们的基线即使 是否有贸易战
ongoing talks and the communications between the two sides and the kind of
正在进行的会谈和沟通 两侧之间以及那种
attention being to tiny wires in the trade rounds are a little bit
注意的是细小的电线 贸易回合有点
decelerating, at least for now, in the next several months.
至少目前来看，增速正在放缓 接下来的几个月。
So the US needs China to buy their energy, agriculture, goods and maybe
所以美国需要中国购买他们的产品 能源、农业、商品，或许还有
outlets. China needs us to reduce their tariffs
网点。 中国需要我们降低关税
and maybe relaxing some kind of restrictions on tech.
也许可以放松一下 对技术的限制。
Okay. And by most indications, those things
好的。 从大多数迹象来看，这些事情
are still on track. Nick, thank you so much for for coming
仍在正轨上。 尼克，非常感谢你的到来
here and making all of those components for us.
在这里并制作所有这些 为我们提供组件。
They're adding John, senior China economist at UBS Investment Bank.
他们添加了中国高级官员约翰 瑞银投资银行经济学家。
Okay. A couple of things across these markets,
好的。 这些市场中的一些事情，
11 minutes into the Indonesia session. And you know what?
印度尼西亚时段开场 11 分钟。 你知道吗？
Why don't we talk about Indonesia? We'll talk about it in a moment, because
我们为什么不谈谈印度尼西亚呢？ 我们稍后会讨论它，因为
Indonesia fell 3% on Friday and it's now down a further 3% today.
印尼周五下跌3%，现在是 今天进一步下跌3%。
So this is a market that can't catch a break.
所以这是一个无法抓住的市场 打破。
It's underperforming and which is a fairly tall order given
表现不佳 这是一个相当高的命令
most things are actually falling right now.
大多数事情实际上都是正确的 现在。
We'll dig into what else is happening in this market.
我们将深入了解其他地区正在发生的事情 这个市场。
But, yes, make no doubt this is a market they're focusing on as well.
但是，是的，毫无疑问这是一个市场 他们也关注。
We're looking as well at Brent. We get that back to just in terms of the
我们也在关注布伦特。 我们回到刚才的方面
updates coming through. We are entering a third week.
更新即将到来。 我们即将进入第三周。
The updates coming through, of course, out of Twi.
当然，不断更新的内容 出自契维语。
And we are, as you can see on a two day look off highs that we hit in the early
正如您在两天内看到的那样，我们是 关注我们早期触及的高点
goings of the Monday session. We were at about one, two, six.
周一会议的进展。 我们当时大约一、二、六点钟。
We're calling one of four right now. As far as that's concerned, gold is
我们现在正在给四个人中的一个打电话。 就这一点而言，黄金
actually also playing out now. We're below 5000 there and miners are
其实现在也在玩。 我们那里的人数低于 5000，矿工们
actually taking quite a bit of a hit. When you look at some of these gold
实际上受到了相当大的打击。 当你看到其中一些黄金时
mining stocks across the region, they are they are not they're still not
该地区的矿业股，他们 他们不是吗 他们仍然不是
behaving like they should be behaving gold as hum.
表现得像他们应该做的那样 金如嗡嗡。
But, you know, it could be just a positioning thing, as most strategists
但是，你知道，这可能只是一个 正如大多数战略家一样，定位问题
in the sell side tells us here. But there you go.
卖方在这里告诉我们。 但就这样吧。
Gold miners are all falling quite substantially here during mining is down
黄金矿商均大幅下跌 采矿期间这里大幅下降
some 4%. But you are getting much closer to that
约4%。 但你已经离那个目标越来越近了
5000 level for gold once again for subscribers.
黄金再次突破5000关口 订户。
You can also turn to your terminal for more on the Iran war.
您还可以转到您的终端 更多关于伊朗战争的信息。
And of course, that aeco data coming through from China to you live go is
当然，aeco 数据即将到来 从中国到你住的地方是
your function. The latest updates plus commentary
你的职能。 最新更新以及评论
analysis from our expert editors.
我们的专家编辑的分析。
Right. Welcome back to map on your Bloomberg
正确的。 欢迎回到彭博社地图
terminal 30 day look vessels of course, on your screens in blue.
当然，码头 30 天看船， 在你的屏幕上显示为蓝色。
This is the Strait of Hormuz, Persian Gulf, Oman, Gulf major exporting hub, of
这是波斯的霍尔木兹海峡 海湾, 阿曼, 海湾主要出口中心,
course, in Iran, which was attacked on the weekend.
当然，在遭到袭击的伊朗 周末。
And some reporting today, that from Axios that the US president is weighing
今天的一些报道来自 美国总统正在权衡的axios
a seizure of some other assets in that part of the world.
扣押其中的一些其他资产 世界的一部分。
We're also getting some lines coming through out of Dubai and the
我们也收到了一些线路 穿过迪拜和
international airport. They are being temporarily suspended
国际机场。 他们被暂时停职
about 30 minutes back. And we're also trying to figure out
大约30分钟回来。 我们也在试图弄清楚
really what tanker traffic is really like given a lot of reports.
油轮运输到底是什么 就像给出了很多报告一样。
Right. If you're Chinese or Russian linked.
正确的。 如果您是中国人或俄罗斯人。
Yeah, free passage of everything but American and Israeli all to get free
是的，一切都可以自由通行，但是 美国人和以色列人都想获得自由
passage. On the Bloomberg terminal, you do have
通道。 在彭博终端上，您确实有
some data on this it's we're looking at 24 hour rolling data every 30 minutes.
我们正在查看这方面的一些数据 24 小时滚动数据，每 30 分钟一次。
So suffice to say, if there's something there that is visible that is moving,
我只想说，如果有什么 那里可见正在移动的东西，
then this might be able to capture that. It's also worth pointing out, though,
那么这也许能够捕捉到这一点。 不过，还值得指出的是，
that some of the tankers in that part of the world have maybe turned off some
那部分的一些油轮 世界可能已经关闭了一些
other signaling mechanisms in order to, of course, avoid There's a lot of
其他信号机制， 当然，避免有很多
jamming that's taking place across Gpps. So that's also affecting the ability of
Gpps 中正在发生干扰。 所以这也影响了能力
folks to figure out really where things are in real time.
人们要弄清楚事情到底在哪里 是实时的。
But based on our understanding, it's effectively at about near zero as far as
但根据我们的理解， 有效地大约接近于零
tanker traffic is concerned. Whether that's the orange line is bi
油轮运输受到关注。 橙色线是否是双
directional, east to west is in blue, west to east is in yellow.
方向性，从东到西为蓝色， 从西向东为黄色。
But again, suffice to say the headline here, Yvonne tells you everything to
但话又说回来，标题就够了 在这里，Yvonne 告诉你一切
know and you are getting a lot more efforts, of course, on many sides to
知道并且你会得到更多 当然，需要多方面的努力
open up traffic there in that part of the world.
在那部分开放交通 世界。
It is interesting to if you read more from this Axios report of what President
如果你读得更多，这很有趣 总统的 Axios 报告
Trump wants to do when it comes to that export hub of Iran, which did attack.
特朗普想做的事 伊朗的出口中心确实遭到了袭击。
So apart from just asking for a coalition of countries to reopen the
所以除了只是要求一个 国家联盟重新开放
Strait of Hormuz, he is also weighing a seizure of the critical oil depot on
霍尔木兹海峡，他也在权衡 扣押关键油库
Kharg Island. This would be a move that would require
哈格岛。 此举需要
U.S. boots on the ground, according to Axios
美国 根据 Axios 的说法，靴子在地面上
here. And if tankers remain bottled up in the
这里。 如果油轮仍然被困在
Persian Gulf. So that's the latest on that front.
波斯湾。 这是这方面的最新情况。
Of course, we have to take a look at when it comes to the impact on China.
当然，我们还得看看 说到对中国的影响。
Right. And and most of the economists and China
正确的。 以及大多数经济学家和中国
watchers that we talked to have talked about, you know, China's efforts to
与我们交谈过的观察者已经交谈过 你知道，中国的努力
build out its energy sources is actually getting fresh momentum from this
建立其能源实际上是 从中获得新的动力
conflict in the Middle East. And Beijing is one of the largest global
中东冲突。 北京是全球最大的城市之一
investors in power grids. And China was the fastest growing LNG
电网投资者。 中国是液化天然气增长最快的国家
market before Russia's invasion of Ukraine in 2020 triggered a surge in
俄罗斯入侵前的市场 2020年乌克兰引发人口激增
spot prices. But Bloomberg opinion columnist David
现货价格。 但彭博社观点专栏作家大卫
Fickling says there is a lesson to be learned in Beijing's dash for gas.
菲克林说有一个教训 吸取了北京大力发展天然气的教训。
He joins us now together with our reporter Dan Murtaugh, to talk us
他现在和我们一起加入我们 记者 Dan Murtaugh 来采访我们
through this complex issue right now. David, let me start with you.
现在解决这个复杂的问题。 大卫，让我从你开始。
Underscore the premise here for us. Yeah, I think this is looking at I was
为我们强调这里的前提。 是的，我想这就是我在看的
looking at a very specific case, really, which is, you know, some of the things
看看一个非常具体的案例，真的， 你知道，其中一些事情
that have caused these blue skies around Beijing in recent years.
造成了周围的蓝天 北京近几年。
You remember like ten years ago, there was a lot of a lot of air pollution in
你还记得十年前，那里 空气污染严重
northern China, especially in winter. One of the things that's really changed
中国北方，尤其是冬天。 真正改变的事情之一
that is that since about 2017, there's been a lot of push for people in rural
也就是说，大约从 2017 年开始， 对农村人来说有很大的推动力
areas to stop burning coal in domestic furnaces to to warm themselves in
国内部分地区停止燃煤 炉子里取暖
winter. And that's pushed people in several
冬天。 这促使人们在几个方面
directions. One has been to electric heaters and
方向。 一种是电热水器，
some to heat pumps, but a lot of them have also been pushed to to gas boilers.
有些用于热泵，但很多 也已被推向燃气锅炉。
And that's actually caused real problems just in this past winter.
这实际上造成了真正的问题 就在刚刚过去的这个冬天。
We saw quite a lot of reports in January with some of these rural families the
一月份我们看到了很多报道 对于其中一些农村家庭来说
they were initially subsidised to to install gas boilers.
他们最初得到的补贴是 安装燃气锅炉。
They were subsidized for the price of the gas.
他们获得了价格补贴 气体。
And those subsidies have gradually been removed because, of course, a lot of
而这些补贴也逐渐被 删除当然是因为很多
local governments in China, you know, are facing a lot of fiscal pressure and
中国的地方政府，你知道， 面临着巨大的财政压力
that's left some of these quite shocking reports out of China of 2026, where
这让其中一些非常令人震惊 2026年中国报道，其中
you've got poor rural families who can't afford to heat their houses, who are,
你有贫困的农村家庭，他们无法 有能力给他们的房子取暖，
you know, people who are having to sort of stand outside in the midday sun to
你知道，那些必须排序的人 站在正午阳光下的户外
get a little bit of warmth and a just like having to rug up inside with extra
得到一点温暖和公正 就像必须在里面加额外的东西
layers of clothing. Now, I think that was a real, real
衣服层数。 现在，我认为那是真实的、真实的
mistake because the costs of heat pumps essentially in a reverse cycle, air
错误是因为热泵的成本 本质上是一个逆循环，空气
conditioners are not much greater for in a lot of these areas, about 20%.
空调并没有大多少 这些领域很多，大约20%。
And really a lot of people talk about gas as this sort of bridge to
确实很多人都在谈论 气体作为这种桥梁
electrification. I think we saw in that Hubei winter gas
电气化。 我想我们在那个湖北冬天看到了煤气
crisis some of the problems to that. And of course, we're seeing spelling out
危机中的一些问题。 当然，我们看到拼写
of the crisis in the Middle East some of the problems for that much more broadly
中东危机的一些 更广泛的问题
in the world. Yeah, David, you certainly have
在世界上。 是的，大卫，你当然有
highlighted some of the challenges in this whole transition.
强调了一些挑战 这整个转变。
Dan, maybe you can step in and talk about how you know, what is being done
丹，也许你可以介入谈谈 关于你如何知道、正在做什么
now, right? This push to expand China's energy
现在，对吧？ 此举旨在扩大中国能源
infrastructure. And when it comes to passing the power
基础设施。 当谈到传递权力时
grid, what efforts are being done now? Yeah.
网格，现在正在做什么努力？ 是的。
You know, David's exactly right. I think China has sort of realized that
你知道，大卫是完全正确的。 我认为中国已经意识到这一点
it was too reliant. You know, it requires about 50% of its
太依赖了。 你知道，它需要大约 50% 的
gas coming from overseas markets, about 70% of its oil coming from overseas
来自海外市场的天然气，约 70%的石油来自海外
markets. So it's really exposed to any gyrations
市场。 所以它真的会受到任何回转的影响
in global prices. And now it looks at electricity, which
在全球价格中。 现在它着眼于电力，
is mostly coming from domestic sources coal, nuclear, wind, solar or
大部分来自国内 煤炭、核能、风能、太阳能或
hydropower, all of which are, you know, produced in China.
水力发电，所有这些，你知道， 中国生产。
So it has a lot more control over the prices and supply there.
所以它对 那里的价格和供应。
And so it's been shifting its economy over the last couple of decades toward
所以它一直在改变经济 在过去的几十年里
more and more electricity. Electricity mostly.
越来越多的电力。 主要是电。
You see that in EVs. But, you know, you can see it out in the
你可以在电动汽车中看到这一点。 但是，你知道，你可以在
countryside with these huge wind and solar farms.
乡村有这些大风 太阳能发电场。
And that's all that is doing is requiring a much stronger grid buildout.
这就是所做的一切 需要更强大的电网建设。
And so you have these companies like state grid and southern grid that are
所以你有这些公司 国家电网、南方电网
backed by the government and are spending record amounts and selling
得到政府的支持并且 支出创纪录金额并销售
bonds for 700 plus billion yuan last year to raise the money to build the
最后发行700余亿元债券 年筹集资金建造
power lines and the batteries that are needed to keep pace with all this new
电源线和电池 需要跟上所有这些新的步伐
electricity demand that's here in China. Yeah.
中国的电力需求。 是的。
So, Dan, just a follow up on that. He talked about financing.
那么，丹，这只是后续行动。 他谈到了融资。
So clearly some of the Saudis have been tapping the markets, whether that's the
很明显，一些沙特人已经 开拓市场，无论是
banks or the debt markets, there's a lot of money that's pushing through into
银行或债务市场，有很多 投入的资金
that. Talk to us, though, about the challenges
那。 不过，请与我们谈谈挑战
that remain despite all that money being in place.
尽管有那么多钱，但仍然存在 就位。
Really? Yeah, I mean, the big challenge is, is
真的吗？ 是的，我的意思是，最大的挑战是
not building the infrastructure. Right.
不建设基础设施。 正确的。
China's got incredible power construction companies.
中国拥有不可思议的力量 建筑公司。
So the long distance power lines, the battery storage plants, like they can
所以长距离电力线， 电池储能工厂，就像他们可以的那样
build those things at scale. The challenge in China is really more
大规模建造这些东西。 中国的挑战确实更大
about under the underlying market that dictates how electrons are moved, where
大约在基础市场下 决定了电子如何移动，在哪里
they go from, how flexible the supply can be with all these new sources of
他们来自哪里，供应有多灵活 可以与所有这些新的来源
wind and solar that can be kind of anywhere geographically, but only on a
风能和太阳能 地理上的任何地方，但仅限于
certain amount of time. And so the real challenge is going to be
一定的时间。 所以真正的挑战是
over the next couple of years to see if China's leaders can can kind of slowly
看看未来几年是否 中国领导人可以慢慢地
reform their market to create a more flexible system without kind of reducing
改革市场以创造更多 灵活的系统，无需减少
any of the energy security promises they've made to their industries and
任何能源安全承诺 他们为自己的行业做出了贡献
people. And you talked about the challenges.
人们。 您谈到了挑战。
Do you get a sense that there's policymakers are trying to fix this
你是否感觉到有 政策制定者正在努力解决这个问题
anyway? And what's sort of the lesson to the
反正？ 这给我们带来了什么教训
rest of the world right now when it comes to trying to transition and make
世界其他地方现在当它 试图转型并做出
this big transition? Yeah, I mean, I think we I mean, Dan and
这个大转变？ 是的，我是说，我想我们是说，丹和
I worked on a story a couple of years ago about the big settlement of captured
我花了几年时间写一个故事 关于被俘虏的大定居点之前
Tong Wei, that bear their founder. I remember the two sessions last year
童薇，就是熊他们的创始人。 我记得去年的两次会议
was talking about, well, you know, if we keep on this electrification process, we
正在谈论，嗯，你知道，如果我们 继续这个电气化进程，我们
can stop all imports within, I think, two decades, which obviously quite a
我认为可以停止所有进口 二十年，这显然是相当
long time. That's two decades of our imports.
很久。 这是我们二十年的进口量。
But for a country the size of China and oil import the size of China, that
但对于中国这样一个幅员辽阔的国家来说 石油进口量相当于中国的规模
that's the sort of scale of ambition that that's being talked about.
这就是野心的规模 正在讨论的那个。
And certainly for China's export industries as well.
当然对于中国的出口 行业也是如此。
A lot of them you're seeing a lot of like EVs and solar panels going to
其中很多你都见过很多 就像电动汽车和太阳能电池板一样
emerging markets that are still very dependent on on fossil fuel imports.
新兴市场仍然非常 依赖化石燃料进口。
And we're going to see in South Asia, Southeast Asia, a lot of exposure to the
我们将在南亚看到， 东南亚地区，接触较多
effects of the crisis we're seeing in the Middle East.
我们所看到的危机的影响 中东。
And China's standing there with the products, the sort of alternative
而中国也站在那里 产品，某种替代品
products to to fix that problem. Hmm.
产品来解决这个问题。 唔。
David, Dan, thank you so much. Great discussion there.
大卫，丹，非常感谢你们。 那里有很棒的讨论。
That was Dan Murtaugh and our opinion columnist David Fickling there talking
这是 Dan Murtaugh 和我们的观点 专栏作家大卫·菲克林在那里讲话
really about this dash for gas in the face of this Iran conflict and what
真正关于汽油的冲刺 面对这场伊朗冲突以及什么
really the world can learn from China. And later on, on Bloomberg TV, we'll be
世界确实可以向中国学习。 稍后，在彭博电视上，我们将
speaking with the Cambodian minister of Mines and Energy, who'll be joining us
与柬埔寨外交部长交谈 矿业和能源，谁将加入我们
exclusively later to explain how the country is working to cushion the impact
稍后专门解释如何 国家正在努力缓解影响
of the Iran war that's happening at the Times when your screen.
正在发生的伊朗战争 当你的屏幕的时候。
This is Bloomberg.
这是布隆伯格。
Right. An update of the energy complex in the
正确的。 能源综合体的更新
in the energy space. Mixed impacts, of course, is created in
在能量空间中。 当然，混合影响是在
Japan. You have Woodside, which is in Oz and a
日本。 你有伍德赛德（Woodside），它位于奥兹国，还有一个
few other players, of course, Petro China, mixed bag there, 1.2%.
当然还有其他几个球员，Petro 中国的情况好坏参半，为1.2%。
We're still above one zero 100 jobs really is what matters there for markets
我们的工作岗位数量仍高于零 100 对于市场而言，真正重要的是
on Brent auto stop. Yeah it seems like when I came the Brent
布伦特自动停止。 是的，好像我来布伦特的时候
price that we've popped up a little bit higher after that Dubai incident and
我们稍微调高的价格 迪拜事件后走高
they basically temporarily shut the international airport there due to a
他们基本上暂时关闭了 那里的国际机场由于
drone incident that caused a fire in a fuel tank nearby.
无人机事件引发火灾 附近有油箱。
So that is the latest when it comes to situation in the city here.
这是最新的 这里的城市情况。
But we take it what it comes to auto stocks.
但我们对汽车的态度是一样的 股票。
Yes, that's where it's really getting hit as well, just given the fuel impact.
是的，这就是真正的意义所在 考虑到燃料的影响，也会受到影响。
Given the oil impact. There you go.
考虑到石油的影响。 就这样吧。
Hyundai Motor, they're down some 3% this morning.
现代汽车，今年下跌了约 3% 早上。
Isuzu also down some 4%. Putting more coming up.
五十铃也下跌了约 4%。 即将推出更多内容。
This is Bloomberg.
这是布隆伯格。
When I am in Tokyo. Japanese markets are.
当我在东京的时候。 日本市场是。
He's at lunch break in just a moment. Yeah, we could be needing a bit of a
他一会儿就到午休时间了。 是的，我们可能需要一些
breather here. We see our stocks are declining some
在这里喘口气。 我们看到我们的库存正在下降
more than 1% in the Nikkei as well as in the topics here today.
日经指数和 今天的话题就到这里。
We talked about the auto sector that certainly has been feeling in dollar
我们谈到了汽车行业 肯定对美元有感觉
yen. We're getting back to those 160 levels
日元。 我们又回到了 160 个关卡
right now. So certainly one thing to watch as well.
现在。 所以当然还有一件事值得关注。
Did you see yields are just one basis point lower.
您是否看到收益率只是一个基础 点更低。
Yeah, you got to wonder right to the last time we talked about when 60 was
是的，你一定想知道 上次我们谈到60岁的时候
intervention risk. But you got to wonder, this time around,
干预风险。 但你一定想知道，这一次，
the dynamics are very different from that point in time.
动力学与 那个时间点。
It's not about yen weakness to dollar strength across the board.
这与日元兑美元疲软无关 全面实力。
So you wonder whether this is something that authorities will look through, can
所以你想知道这是否是某事 当局将会调查，可以
look through, although that is, of course inflationary, which then goes
看看，虽然那是 当然是通货膨胀，然后
into this massive central bank week. We'll have in a moment here.
进入这个大规模的央行周。 我们一会儿就在这里。
The rest of the region, though, is, I would like to say, doing and holding up
不过，该地区的其他地区，我 想说、做、坚持
okay. I'd be lying to you, though, if I did
好的。 但如果我这么做的话，我就是在骗你
that. We're down about half of 1%.
那。 我们下降了大约 1% 的一半。
Most of the pain points, though, I think are fairly expected and straightforward.
不过，我认为大多数痛点 是相当预期和简单的。
You obviously have the energy related sectors like autos, shipping airlines
你显然有与能量相关的 汽车、航运航空公司等行业
obviously are taking a bit of a hit today.
显然受到了一些打击 今天。
You're also getting, though, Indonesia, which is also acting up quite a bit.
不过，你也会得到印度尼西亚， 这也表现得相当不错。
We're down about 2%, the underperforming market across Asia Pacific.
我们下跌了约 2%，表现不佳 整个亚太地区的市场。
It's also worth pointing out, though, that the Chinese data that's come
不过，还值得指出的是， 来的中国数据
through in the last hour, whether that's home prices or activity numbers, have
在过去的一个小时里，无论是 房价或活动数量，有
just about beat across the board. So better than expected, almost across
几乎全线击败。 比想象的好，几乎跨越了
the board, I say almost because the jobless rate actually ticked up to 5.3%.
董事会，我说几乎是因为 失业率实际上上升至5.3%。
But that's not necessarily a bad thing, too, because you might also getting me
但这不一定是坏事 也是，因为你也可能会得到我
might also have the labor force implications off there.
可能还有劳动力 那里的影响。
But anyway, economic numbers have been decent.
但无论如何，经济数据已经 体面的。
The geopolitical backdrop has been complex and difficult, and that's really
地缘政治背景 复杂且困难，这确实是
offset most of the good stuff we've seen from the actual economic numbers.
抵消了我们见过的大部分好东西 从实际经济数据来看。
Yeah, and of course, this data came before this whole Iran concept, right?
是的，当然，这个数据来了 在整个伊朗概念之前，对吧？
So that certainly is still a bit dated, but certainly there's going to be a lot
所以这肯定还是有点过时了， 但肯定会有很多
of commentary that's happening in this Beijing presser here right now.
正在发生的评论 北京记者现在就到这里。
We'll see if they talk anything about the Iran impact potentially when it
我们会看看他们是否谈论任何事情 伊朗的潜在影响
comes to, of course, global demand for exports and this export machine that
当然，这涉及到全球的需求 出口和这台出口机器
China has really been able to, you know, undergo to really offset what's happened
中国确实能够，你知道， 经历真正抵消所发生的事情
domestically, whether that sort of continues here in 2026 in terms of the
在国内，无论是那种 2026 年将继续
central bank decisions to tell you about, that certainly is the big thing
央行决策告诉你 关于，这当然是件大事
to watch, right when you talk about the Fed, the UK, B or ECB, I mean, it's all
就在你谈论的时候观看 美联储、英国、英国央行或欧洲央行，我的意思是，这一切
the major central banks. So they're going to, I'm sure, be asked
主要中央银行。 所以我确信他们会被问到
to address the situation when it comes to the oil price shock.
以便在情况发生时解决 到油价冲击。
And what does this mean for the whole reaction function of central banks now?
这对整体意味着什么 现在央行的反应功能是什么？
It will be the first direct message we're getting from the major central
这将是第一条直接消息 我们从主要中央车站
banks, how they're looking at this spike.
银行，他们如何看待这个问题 尖峰。
Yes. And whether they can look through or
是的。 他们是否可以看穿或
whether they'll need to be reactive. In fact, the very first, I would say, to
他们是否需要做出反应。 事实上，我想说的是，首先
even likely move is going to be the RBA, which is tomorrow.
甚至可能采取行动的是澳大利亚央行， 这是明天。
And that's that's a coin toss. Right.
这就是抛硬币。 正确的。
And don't be surprised if this time tomorrow we'll be looking at a rate hike
如果这一次，请不要感到惊讶 明天我们将考虑加息
coming to either the RBA. The rest of the region, as you can see,
来到澳大利亚央行。 正如你所看到的，该地区的其他地区
will be hold, but they'll it's really what they say and how they say it.
会被保留，但他们真的会 他们说什么以及他们怎么说。
Yeah, for now it seems to be the market is more worried about the inflation
是的，目前看来是市场 更担心通胀
impact, I think. How much further do we have to start
影响，我认为。 我们还需要多远才能开始
thinking about the growth impact if this situation prolongs.
考虑这对增长的影响 情况延长。
So certainly there's a lot of things that makes it much more complex for
所以肯定有很多事情 这使得事情变得更加复杂
these central bankers here to kind of deal with not just the oil price shock,
这些央行行长来这里是为了 不仅要应对油价冲击，
but also the stagflation sort of concerns that are somewhat weighing on
还有滞胀 一些令人担忧的问题
this these markets here right now. Let's give the situation when it comes
这些市场现在就在这里。 让我们给出当时的情况
to Dubai. Now, authorities have suspended flights
到迪拜。 目前，当局已暂停航班
at the Dubai International Airport. This is hours after a drone strike
在迪拜国际机场。 这是无人机袭击数小时后
targeted facilities near the airfield. Let's get the latest now from our
机场附近的目标设施。 现在让我们从我们的网站获取最新信息
Bloomberg Middle East anchor, Jomana Versace.
彭博社中东主播 Jomana 范思哲。
She joins us from Dubai. Jomana, what do we know at this point?
她从迪拜加入我们。 Jomana，目前我们知道什么？
What's the latest? Yeah, well, the latest actually is we
最新消息是什么？ 是的，好吧，最新的实际上是我们
just got a message put up on air by the Dubai media office.
刚刚收到一条消息 迪拜媒体办公室。
And they have said that civil defense teams have successfully contained the
他们说民防 团队已成功遏制
fire resulting from an impact to one of the fuel tanks in the vicinity of the
因撞击其中之一而引起火灾 附近的油箱
city's international airport. They go on to add that there have been
城市的国际机场。 他们接着补充说，已经有
no injuries caused. Limited damage on the back of it.
没有造成伤害。 背面的损坏有限。
But of course, earlier on, the Dubai Civil Aviation Authority said that they
当然，早些时候，迪拜 民航局表示，他们
were temporarily suspending some flights.
暂时暂停了一些 航班。
And indeed, if you look at Emirates, for example, they have put up a post
事实上，如果你看看阿联酋航空，就会发现 例如，他们发布了一个帖子
advising anyone who was coming to the airport to no longer come to the airport
建议任何前来的人 机场不再来机场
until it is safe to do so. Precautionary measure, of course, what I
直到安全为止。 当然，预防措施是我所采取的
will say is that this is the first attack on the airport in about a week.
会说这是第一个 大约一周后将袭击机场。
It's been a few days now where we've seen a resumed level of activity,
现在已经过去几天了 我们看到活动水平有所恢复，
especially from some of the local carriers that Emirates had been
尤其是来自一些当地的 阿联酋航空曾是的承运商
operating with a lot more capacity in the last couple of days and flights were
以更大的容量运行 最近几天的航班
sort of returning back to normal. But of course, this sets things back a
有点恢复正常了。 但当然，这会让事情倒退
thought back to where we were. A temporary suspension.
回想一下我们当时在哪里。 暂时停业。
But what I will say is that yesterday the UAE announced that they have
但我要说的是昨天 阿联酋宣布他们已经
received. Over 1600 drones directed from Iran.
已收到。 超过 1600 架无人机来自伊朗。
Most of them successfully intercepted around 300 missiles.
大部分都成功拦截 大约300枚导弹。
Also, interception rate very high. They're above 19 92%.
而且拦截率非常高。 他们超过19 92%。
But the point is, it is these 17 of this war, the projectiles keep coming.
但重点是，就是这17个 战争，炮弹不断袭来。
And if anything, what Iran are doing now is they seem to be targeting very
如果有的话，那就是伊朗现在正在做什么 他们似乎瞄准了非常
strategic locations once again. And in this case, they appear to have
再次成为战略要地。 在这种情况下，他们似乎有
targeted a fuel depot by the Dubai International Airport.
迪拜的目标是一个燃料库 国际机场。
And, of course, lots of retaliatory talk over the weekend for many of these
当然，还有很多报复性言论 对于其中许多人来说，周末
senior Iranian leaders, suggesting that the attack, the U.S.
伊朗高级领导人表示 此次袭击，美国
attack on Kharg Island could have broader ramifications for the Gulf
对哈格岛的袭击可能会 对海湾地区产生更广泛的影响
states, warning that any place that is harboring U.S.
状态，警告任何地方 庇护美国
assets, even U.S. nationals in Iran, the ports around some
资产，甚至美国 伊朗国民，一些周围的港口
of the strategic locations could be fair targets.
的战略位置可能是公平的 目标。
So here we are. This is just one manifestation of that.
所以我们到了。 这只是其中的一种表现。
But for now, the Dubai media office saying that the fire is contained.
但目前，迪拜媒体办公室 说火势已被控制。
No injuries have been caused. Jomana, what do we know about this?
没有造成人员受伤。 乔马纳，我们对此了解多少？
I mean, a few hours ago, talk around the US president, the White House, asking
我的意思是，几个小时前，谈论 美国总统、白宫询问
other countries to do some heavy lifting, to participate in being able to
其他国家做一些重 提升，参与能够
secure the Strait of Hormuz. What do we know about that?
确保霍尔木兹海峡的安全。 我们对此了解多少？
Yeah, well, you have to distinguish between what the U.S.
是啊，你得区分一下 美国之间
are doing militarily in Iran and versus their actions to try to reopen the
在伊朗进行军事行动并与 他们试图重新开放的行动
straits by force. And clearly, they're considering a
以武力海峡。 显然，他们正在考虑
number of options here. Remember, a few days ago, they talked
这里的选项数量。 记得前几天他们还聊过
about the possibility of introducing naval escorts and those lower insurance
关于引入的可能性 海军护航和保险较低的
premiums for vessels that wanted to take through to pass through.
想要搭乘的船只的保费 通过来通过。
Now they're leaning on a different strategy, which is to help build up this
现在他们依靠不同的 战略，旨在帮助建立这一
coalition of different countries to help ensure the safe passage of vessels
不同国家联合起来提供帮助 确保船舶安全通行
through the straits. And their thinking.
通过海峡。 还有他们的想法。
There is predominantly it's Asian countries that are benefiting from the
主要是亚洲人 从中受益的国家
transit of oil that is going through the strait.
石油过境 海峡。
I mean, China, the biggest buyer by far of Iranian oil, around 90% of Iranian
我的意思是，中国是迄今为止最大的买家 伊朗石油的90%左右
oil does get directed to China. About 13% of China's overall oil imports
石油确实被直接运往中国。 约占中国石油进口总量的13%
come from Iran. Israel, about 50% of the seaborne oil
来自伊朗。 以色列，约50%的海运石油
that goes through the strait goes to China.
穿过海峡去往 中国。
So China a key player here. And Trump's calculus is that if they
所以中国是这里的关键参与者。 特朗普的盘算是，如果他们
want to continue getting that oil, then they also need to participate in
想继续获得这种油，那么 他们还需要参与
ensuring the safety of the strait. Now, one thing that is also dangled is a
确保海峡安全。 现在，还有一件事也悬而未决，那就是
potential delay of that meeting, the Trump XI meeting later on this month, as
该会议可能会延迟， 特朗普十一世将于本月晚些时候举行会议，
I'm sure you guys are very well aware. He's also signaled the same with other
我相信你们都很清楚。 他也向其他人发出了同样的信号
NATO members. He's encouraging U.K., France to get
北约成员国。 他鼓励英国和法国
involved as well, otherwise warning that they could pay a diplomatic price and
也参与其中，否则警告 他们可以付出外交代价
interview he said that overnight, too. So a mixture of a desire to build a
接受采访时他说，隔夜也一样。 因此，混合了建立一个
coalition, but also his typical diplomatic wrangling.
联盟，也是他的典型 外交角力。
What I will say from the Iranian perspective is their sense that they are
我要从伊朗人那里说的话 观点是他们对自己的感觉
willing themselves to cut deals with certain countries.
愿意与他们达成协议 某些国家。
And indeed, there were reports over the weekend that they managed to cut a deal
事实上，有报道称 周末他们成功达成协议
with India to secure the safe passage of a couple of vessels there.
与印度确保安全通行 那里有几艘船。
India, also a key buyer of Iranian oil. So maybe that is the template that the
印度也是伊朗石油的主要买家。 所以也许这就是模板
Iranians are looking for and the future where they can cut these side deals with
伊朗人正在寻找未来 他们可以在那里达成这些附带协议
their biggest buyers. But of course, the Trump administration
他们最大的买家。 但当然，特朗普政府
is pushing for a more global solution now to the Strait of Hormuz.
正在推动更加全球化的解决方案 现在到霍尔木兹海峡。
I mean, we won't need a global solution if the deal that we could talk about
我的意思是，我们不需要全球解决方案 如果我们可以谈论的交易
would be a deal that brings Iran and the U.S.
这将是一项让伊朗和 美国
back to the table. How far do you think we are from that
回到桌子上。 你认为我们离那个目标还有多远
point in time, Jomana? So President Trump customary.
时间点，乔马纳？ 特朗普总统也是如此。
I'm very, very busy over the weekend giving interviews.
周末我非常非常忙 接受采访。
He did give an interview to NBC over Saturday night, and he suggested that
他确实接受了 NBC 的采访 星期六晚上，他建议
he's willing to make a deal with the Iranians, but they're not where he wants
他愿意与 伊朗人，但他们不是他想要的地方
them to be. And then when he was pressed for more
他们是。 然后当他被要求更多时
information on exactly what he was looking for out of them, he didn't give
关于他到底是什么的信息 寻找他们，他没有给
a lot more color. But he did say and this is something
更多颜色。 但他确实说过，这是一件事
that the U.S. has maintained since the beginning of
美国 自年初以来一直保持着
this war, even before the war, that Iran can never have the ability to possess a
这场战争，甚至在战争之前，伊朗 永远不可能有能力拥有
nuclear weapon. Now, on the other side, the Iranians
核武器。 现在，在另一边，伊朗人
continue to be defiant. If you look at the language coming
继续挑衅。 如果你看看即将到来的语言
through from the foreign minister, from the Supreme Council chief, the Security
外交部长通过 最高委员会主席、安全
Council chief, Ali Larijani. They say that they are going to continue
理事会主席阿里·拉里贾尼。 他们表示将继续
to fight back so long as U.S. and Israeli joint operations continue.
只要美国就能反击 与以色列的联合行动仍在继续。
But one thing that they have said is they would return back to the
但他们说过的一件事是 他们会回到
negotiating table if they can get guarantees that a strike like this would
如果他们能得到谈判桌 保证像这样的罢工
never happen again. They do not want to be attacked again.
永远不会再发生。 他们不想再次受到攻击。
And even though the U.S. and Israeli operations have been
而且尽管美国 以色列的行动已经
militarily very successful from the Iranians perspective, so long as the
军事上非常成功 伊朗人的观点是，只要
regime is still intact, as long as it comes out the other side still existing,
政权仍然完好无损，只要它 出来另一面仍然存在，
then that is a win for them. And their judgment is that they will
那么这对他们来说就是一场胜利。 他们的判断是他们会
continue to inflict as much economic cost on the region and on the globe to
继续造成尽可能多的经济损失 该地区和全球的成本
ensure that these types of strikes don't happen again.
确保此类罢工不会 再次发生。
It's a it's a form of deterrence. And at this point, there is no real
这是一种威慑形式。 而此时，还没有真正的
signs that they're ready to come to the negotiating table because they realize
有迹象表明他们已经准备好来 谈判桌因为他们意识到
how much leverage they have on that specific Strait of Hormuz choke points
他们对此有多大影响力 霍尔木兹海峡的具体咽喉要道
and on the ability to level damage on the Gulf states.
以及对等级伤害的能力 海湾国家。
Even with these lower costing drones, which they can.
即使使用这些成本较低的无人机， 他们可以。
They're sitting on reportedly a stockpile of 50,000 of, but can still
据报道，他们坐在 囤货5万个，但还可以
cause a significant amount of damage and disruption, as we saw, for example, this
造成重大损害并且 颠覆，正如我们所看到的，例如，
morning with Dubai Airport, they targeted a fuel that point which caused
早上与迪拜机场，他们 瞄准了导致该点的燃料
a temporary suspension of some flights. Yeah.
暂时停止部分航班。 是的。
As you point out, right back to the first point you made.
正如你所指出的，回到 你提出的第一点。
Back to the first one in a week. Jomana, thank you.
回到一周内的第一个。 乔马纳，谢谢你。
Well, we'll let you go. Of course, you've a busy show.
好吧，我们会让你走。 当然，你的演出很繁忙。
Ahead, Gianni Versace, their horizons, Middle East and Africa anchor in Dubai
前方，詹尼·范思哲，他们的视野， 中东和非洲锚定迪拜
for us. Back to the other story we're tracking.
对于我们来说。 回到我们正在追踪的另一个故事。
And this actually has to do with the Chinese briefing that's taking place.
这实际上与 中方正在举行简报会。
But it relates to the Iran story. And officials are saying that they are
但这与伊朗的故事有关。 官员们表示，他们正在
closely watching the risks from the energy price spike despite a solid
密切关注风险 尽管能源价格坚挺，但仍飙升
supply base, meaning supplies are not so much an issue, but obviously the pass
供应基地，意味着供应情况并非如此 这是一个很大的问题，但显然是通行证
through and as far as global prices are concerned, is something that they are
直至全球价格 关心的是他们所关心的事情
tracking very closely. They're also looking at, again, robust
跟踪非常密切。 他们也在寻找稳健的
energy buffers in the event we do get these price swings and, of course,
如果我们确实得到了能量缓冲 这些价格波动，当然，
supply, that is really, really hard to come by.
供应，真的非常非常难 过来。
Yeah, And you talk about when it came to the overall data, which was better than
是的，你谈到了 整体数据，优于
expected on multiple fronts apart from the unemployment, sort of the employment
预计在多个方面除了 失业，某种就业
numbers, I think everything else was a beat.
数字，我认为其他一切都是 击败。
You know, they're talking about when it comes to what we saw in January and Fab,
你知道，他们正在谈论什么时候 谈到我们在一月份和 Fab 所看到的情况，
it does set a solid foundation for achieving that full year target for
它确实为 实现全年目标
2026. As you know, it has been a soft target
2026 年。 如你所知，它一直是一个软目标
of four and a half to 5%. But yes, they seem to have showing some
四个半到 5%。 但是，是的，他们似乎表现出了一些
confidence that, you know, this is starting to be the early signs of them
相信，你知道，这是 开始成为他们的早期迹象
being able to achieve that new target. Also, when it comes to the chip price
能够实现这个新目标。 另外，说到芯片价格
increase, he says that also indicates domestic computing demand.
他说，这也表明 国内计算需求。
So still talking about the innovation, all that kind of sort of thing is really
所以还是说创新， 所有这类事情确实是
kind of helping when it comes to how demand and what that picture looks like
谈到如何做时有帮助 需求以及图片是什么样的
right now. Yeah, there we go.
现在。 是的，我们开始吧。
Lots of they're touching on many, many aspects here as pertains at a briefing.
他们中的很多人都触及了很多很多 这里涉及的方面与情况介绍会有关。
I will have more as we get more details coming through out of the briefing in
当我们获得更多详细信息时，我会提供更多信息 从简报中得出
Beijing for our subscribers. We want to get up to speed on both
北京为我们的订阅者服务。 我们希望加快这两方面的步伐
things. On Iran specifically today, we go on
事物。 今天特别是关于伊朗，我们继续
your Bloomberg terminal. We'll bring you all the latest
您的彭博终端。 我们将为您带来最新的一切
developments of the various reports and what we're seeing across these markets
各种报告的进展情况和 我们在这些市场上看到的情况
in reaction or the absence of a reaction to those reports coming through.
有反应或无反应 收到这些报告。
Lots more ahead. This is the China show.
还有更多。 这就是中国秀。
Now. It's a busy way for markets when it
现在。 对于市场来说，这是一种繁忙的方式
comes to central bank meetings, also when it comes to earnings coming up here
也出席央行会议 当谈到这里的收入时
as well to watch this week. So, yes, the tech play certainly is one
本周也值得观看。 所以，是的，科技游戏肯定是其中之一
thing to watch. Tencent, Alibaba, the EVs as well, like
值得关注的事情。 腾讯、阿里巴巴、电动汽车等
Xpeng, you got Geely Li Motor, that's all happening there.
小鹏汽车，你有吉利汽车，那就是 一切都发生在那里。
And of course, in the mix of that, you've got Foxconn, you've got Hon Hai
当然，综合起来， 你有富士康，你有鸿海
and the like. So certainly it's a busy, busy week on
等等。 所以这肯定是忙碌的一周
tap. Costco shipping might be quite telling
轻敲。 Costco 的运输可能很能说明问题
just what they're going to say about the impact from this Iran war.
就是他们要说的 受这次伊朗战争的影响。
Let's start with some of a bit, two big ones here that we're watching very
让我们从一些大的事情开始 我们正在关注的那些
closely right when it comes to Hon. Hai, the Taiwanese tech giant also due
谈到Hon时，非常正确。 台湾科技巨头 Hai 也因
to report later today. For more, let's bring in our Asia tech
今天晚些时候报告。 欲了解更多信息，让我们引入我们的亚洲技术
correspondent, Animal Jewelers. Well, we're expecting we're expecting
记者，动物珠宝商。 嗯，我们期待我们期待
strong results, I think and I say this actually, I say this every month, I
强劲的结果，我认为并且我这么说 事实上，我每个月都会这么说，我
think. But it is the quirk of the Taiwanese
思考。 但这是台湾人的怪癖
stock exchange that the companies that are listed there do need to report their
证券交易所表示，该公司 已列出，确实需要报告他们的
monthly sales figures. So at this point, we already have a very
每月销售数据。 所以此时我们已经有了一个非常
good indication going into the figures, but the expectation is that we're going
数字中有很好的指示， 但我们的期望是我们要去
to see strong results, essentially a 22% increase in quarterly sales.
看到强劲的结果，基本上是 22% 季度销售额增加。
So that does really speak to the server side of the business because of course
这确实对服务器有影响 当然是业务方面
Hon Hai is a company. Yes, it's known as the world's largest
鸿海是一家公司。 是的，它被称为世界上最大的
assembler of Apple iPhones, but actually as well, it's a major partner of Nvidia,
苹果 iPhone 的组装商，但实际上 它也是 Nvidia 的主要合作伙伴，
now a major server assembly partner. So it's really benefiting from all that
现在是主要的服务器组装合作伙伴。 所以它确实受益于这一切
CapEx spending we're seeing from the HYPERSCALERS like Microsoft and Alphabet
我们看到的资本支出 微软和 Alphabet 等超大规模企业
and Amazon and media in the US. And of course those plans continue into
以及美国的亚马逊和媒体。 当然，这些计划会持续到
this year. But but we are looking at sales overall
今年。 但是我们正在关注整体销量
of $92.6 trillion. That's 82.6 billion in the quarter
92.6 万亿美元。 本季度收入为 826 亿美元
ending December and that would be ahead of analyst expectations.
十二月结束，那将是未来 分析师的预期。
I mean, they do give regular guidance on the top line where they don't give those
我的意思是，他们确实会定期提供指导 他们不提供这些的顶行
a breakdown. So things like the device assembly unit,
崩溃。 所以像设备组装单元这样的东西，
how is that, for example, going to do this year?
例如，那会怎样？ 今年？
Yeah, well, that actually is expected to do well because because going into the
是的，好吧，这实际上是预期的 做得好是因为因为进入
fourth quarter, of course, there was the release of the latest iPhone line up and
当然，第四季度 最新 iPhone 系列的发布以及
there was a strong reception to that both in the US but in Apple's other
对此反应强烈 不仅在美国，而且在苹果的其他地区
critical major market and that's China, of course.
关键的主要市场那就是中国， 当然。
So that is going to be a boon for the business.
所以这对 业务。
The question could also be around the currency impact because we saw that
这个问题也可能围绕 货币影响，因为我们看到了
general strengthening trend of the Taiwanese dollar and end of last year,
总体趋强趋势 新台币和去年年底，
of course, it helped the GDP, but it could actually end up being a headwind
当然，它对GDP有所帮助，但它 实际上最终可能会成为逆风
to companies like Hon Hai. The other question, of course, around
像鸿海这样的公司。 当然，另一个问题是围绕
the computer or the PC assembly side, and that actually could end up declining
计算机或PC组装端， 这实际上可能最终会下降
a tough comparison base for that segment of the business.
该细分市场的严格比较基础 的业务。
So yeah, a lot to watch in these numbers and I think as well, just given that
所以，是的，这些数字有很多值得关注的地方 我也认为，考虑到这一点
guidance we get on the outlook and what the company indicates, given we've
我们获得的有关前景和内容的指导 该公司表示，鉴于我们已经
already had monthly sales figures to start 2026 and those as well are
已经有月度销售数据 从 2026 年开始，这些也是
continuing to look strong. All right, Bill, thank you.
继续看起来很强大。 好的，比尔，谢谢你。
And I'll jewelers there with the latest on what to expect when it comes to Hon
我会向那里的珠宝商提供最新的 谈到阁下时会发生什么
Hai. Shifting gears now, let's talk about
哈。 现在换个话题，我们来谈谈
late motor that's also set to report earnings later on.
迟到的电机也将报告 稍后收益。
Bloomberg Intelligence has been crunching the numbers as well.
彭博资讯已 还要处理数字。
They're expecting the automaker to unveil its first annual profit.
他们期望汽车制造商 公布其首个年度利润。
Let's go to our China automotive reporter, Linda Lu.
让我们一起去中国汽车吧 记者，卢琳达。
She joins us now. So first, annual profit, what's been
她现在加入我们了。 首先，年利润是多少
driving that, you think A big driving factor is that they've done really well
驾驶那个，你认为一个大驾驶 因素是他们做得非常好
in sales looking in 2025. They've managed to double their sales
展望 2025 年的销售情况。 他们的销售额成功翻了一番
growing over 100%. So that's a momentum that's really
增长超过100%。 所以这确实是一种势头
lifted their revenues, not to mention their profits.
增加了他们的收入，更不用说 他们的利润。
Obviously, the pressure is going to continue on margins given that the price
显然，压力将 考虑到价格，继续保持利润率
war in China is still raging, although demand for EVs may be on the rise this
尽管中国的战争仍在激烈进行 今年对电动汽车的需求可能会上升
year given we're seeing surging oil prices.
今年我们看到石油价格飙升 价格。
So a lot of a lot of things I think Lee Motor can expect coming into this year.
所以很多很多事情我认为李 Motor预计将于今年上市。
Are we expecting excuse me, any guidance and pricing to the point you're making
请问，我们是否在等待任何指导 并根据您的定价进行定价
on these price points? I think that's going to be a tough one.
在这些价位上？ 我认为这将是一项艰难的任务。
The automakers are balancing all of these kind of pressures within the China
汽车制造商正在平衡所有 中国内部的这些压力
domestic market. Competition is still fierce and the
国内市场。 竞争依然激烈，
government has actually started scaling back subsidies for EV purchases.
政府实际上已经开始扩大规模 支持电动汽车购买补贴。
So there could be flagging demand. But then on the upside, growth into
因此，需求可能会疲软。 但从好的方面来看，增长到
international markets is gaining momentum, especially LEAP Motors trying
国际市场正在崛起 动力，尤其是零跑汽车的尝试
to leverage its partnership with STELLANTIS.
利用与的合作伙伴关系 斯特兰蒂斯。
And like we said, the situation with Iran could be a factor that helps to
正如我们所说，情况 伊朗可能是一个有助于
drive demand for EVs globally. All right, Linda, thank you.
推动全球电动汽车的需求。 好的，琳达，谢谢你。
Linda Liu there, our China automotive reporter, on what to expect for Li Motor
Linda Liu 在那里，我们的中国汽车 记者对理想汽车有何期待
when they report later on today. And yeah, we got a big interview coming
当他们今天晚些时候报告时。 是的，我们有一个重要的采访即将到来
up, too. Yeah, yeah.
也起来了 是啊是啊。
I'm just finding out about this in fact, kidding this time tomorrow.
其实我也是刚刚才知道这个事情 明天这个时候开玩笑。
There we go. The late motor co-president will be
我们开始吧。 已故的汽车联席总裁将是
joining us on the China show. You can catch that exclusive
加入我们的中国展会。 你可以捕捉到那独家的
conversation coming up on The Times on your screen.
《泰晤士报》将进行对话 你的屏幕。
Check that out as well tomorrow. This is one.
明天也检查一下。 这是一个。
Check out some big headlines here we're following for you.
在这里查看一些大头条新闻 为您跟随。
Or watching aluminum prices after aluminum in Bahrain started a phase
或者关注之后的铝价 巴林铝业开始进入一个阶段
production shutdown at the world's largest single site smelter of the
全球工厂停产 最大的单一地点冶炼厂
metal. It's a bid to preserve its inventory of
金属。 这是为了保留其库存
raw materials and keep other parts of the plant operating.
原材料并保留其他部分 工厂正在运营。
Now, all those move comes as the industry faces a spike in prices and
现在，所有这些举措都随着 行业面临价格飙升
traders brace for widespread supply blockages.
贸易商为广泛供应做好准备 堵塞。
In Indonesia, President Prabowo Subianto says he would only consider temporarily
在印度尼西亚，总统普拉博沃·苏比安托 表示他只会暂时考虑
exceeding Indonesia's statutory budget deficit cap for emergency situations.
超出印度尼西亚的法定预算 紧急情况下的赤字上限。
Speaking exclusively with Bloomberg, he says that could only happen if oil
他在接受彭博社独家采访时表示 说这只有在石油的情况下才会发生
prices stay elevated for a sustained period.
价格持续高位运行 期间。
Obama also underscored his commitment to fiscal discipline and says Indonesia
奥巴马还强调了他的承诺 财政纪律并表示印度尼西亚
must live within its means. Australia says one more member of the
必须量入为出。 澳大利亚称又一名成员
Iranian women's soccer team granted asylum by Canberra has decided to return
伊朗女足获准 堪培拉庇护已决定返回
to Iran. That means five out of the original
到伊朗。 这意味着原来的五个
seven who have been given refuge will now return.
七名获得庇护的人将 现在返回。
Now last week Australia granted asylum to six players and a support worker
上周澳大利亚批准了庇护 六名玩家和一名支持人员
after concerns of persecution. When Iranian state media described the
在担心受到迫害之后。 当伊朗官方媒体描述
team as traitors. Okay,
团队为叛徒。 好的，
alright. So how is South Korea dealing with this
好吧。 那么韩国是如何处理这个问题的呢？
energy crisis? What will they plan to do is to be using
能源危机？ 他们计划做的是使用
extra tax revenue to then fund all the support measures coming through in a bid
额外的税收收入可以为所有 竞标中通过的支持措施
really to just cushion the blow to consumers and businesses from obviously
真的只是为了缓冲打击 消费者和企业显然
rising energy prices globally triggered by the war in the Middle East.
全球能源价格上涨引发 受中东战争的影响。
Its finance minister, in fact, on Friday spoke with us exclusively.
事实上，其财政部长周五 与我们独家交谈。
Have a look. To
看看吧。 到
go along here to corroborate that can get to them.
沿着这里去证实可以 去找他们。
Right. Right now, the Middle East situation is
正确的。 当前，中东局势
overshadowing the global economy. The government's top priority right now
给全球经济蒙上阴影。 政府当前的首要任务
is responding to the Middle East situation in the short term, while
正在回应中东 短期内的情况，同时
reducing Korea's structural dependence on oil over the medium to long term.
减少韩国的结构性依赖 中长期来看石油。
Some of that, I guess, which is why you just announced a fuel price cap.
我想，其中一些，这就是为什么你 刚刚宣布了燃油价格上限。
Why this specific measure instead of others more potentially broadly or more
为什么采取这一具体措施而不是 其他更广泛或更广泛的潜力
targeted measures to support the economy, to hunger?
有针对性的支持措施 经济，挨饿？
Isn't it? Currently the imported oil is from
不是吗？ 目前进口石油来自
before the Middle East conflict during this two week period when imports have
中东冲突之前 这两周期间进口量
been halted. It will come in at a higher price.
被叫停。 它将以更高的价格进入。
However, if the future imports become even more expensive, the government
然而，如果未来的进口量变成 更贵的是政府
plans to raise the price proposal accordingly to compensate.
计划提高价格建议 相应地进行补偿。
The government plans to decide at that time whether to reduce taxes again to
政府计划届时做出决定 是否再次减税的时间到
spend on health care. What is the meter if you actually need
花在医疗保健上。 如果您确实需要的话，仪表是多少
to help the refiners? Does that mean that the government will
帮助炼油厂？ 这是否意味着政府将
be using its own budget in order to do that?
使用自己的预算来做 那个？
And how are you planning to pay for that cost increase or might not get
您打算如何支付费用 成本增加或可能得不到
equalised? So therefore, if refiners incur losses
均势？ 因此，如果炼油厂蒙受损失
during this process, the government intends to compensate for those losses.
在此过程中，政府 打算补偿这些损失。
That was South Korean Finance Minister Kun Cho there speaking exclusively to
那是韩国财政部长 Kun Cho 在那里专门发言
Sherry. We'll have more from that conversation
雪利酒。 我们将从这次谈话中获得更多信息
later on, of course, the next hour. Yep.
稍后，当然是下一个小时。 是的。
Before we wrap the show up today, just look at Brent prices, crude prices,
在我们结束今天的演出之前， 看看布伦特原油价格，
generally speaking. And of course, there's the aluminum
一般来说。 当然，还有铝
element as well to track here. Gains across most gold, of course, is
元素也可以在这里跟踪。 当然，大多数黄金的收益是
going the opposite way. Still was below 5000.
朝相反的方向走。 仍然低于5000。
You are still getting pressure across the gold complex in the equity markets
你仍然面临着压力 股票市场的黄金综合体
today. Chinese consumer stocks are actually
今天。 中国消费股实际上
doing quite well, holding up quite resiliently everything from Maotai, of
做得很好，坚持得很好 茅台酒的一切都充满弹性，
course, which is two massive name consumer staple name on the CSI 300 and
当然，这是两个巨大的名字 沪深 300 指数中的消费必需品名称
on shore retail sales to pricing to the upside.
岸上零售销售到定价 好的一面。
The overlay as well from the property side of things is a property market
覆盖层也来自酒店 事情的一面是房地产市场
which is not which is falling by the slowest pace going back to June.
哪个不是哪个正在下降 最慢的速度要追溯到六月。
So just that mental gymnastics things are basically better than expected as it
所以只是心理体操的事 基本上比预期要好，因为它
pertains to the property market. And most metrics that have come through
与房地产市场有关。 大多数已经通过的指标
in the last hour, economics has come out with their sort of initial reaction to
在最后一个小时，经济学已经出来了 他们的初步反应
all this right now. So they said really, it's a good set of
现在这一切。 所以他们说真的，这是一套很好的
numbers, but it was kind of a low bar that the data did clear.
数字，但门槛有点低 数据确实清楚了。
At this moment, they still think the economy is stuck in a sort of slow
此时此刻，他们仍然认为 经济陷入某种缓慢的状态
growth, in a stark reality that, you know, we're still trapped in this slow
成长，在一个严峻的现实中，你 知道吗，我们仍然陷在这缓慢的过程中
growth equilibrium according to their their assessment of it right now.
根据他们的增长平衡 他们现在对此的评估。
So but right now, the market is taking it in stride and say, look, this is at
所以但现在，市场正在采取 它大步流星地说，看，这是在
least some good news in the face of all this volatility and bad news that we're
至少有一些好消息 我们面临的这种波动和坏消息
seeing around the world right now. Yeah.
现在环游世界。 是的。
Yeah, it really is. I think the rates markets are also
是的，确实如此。 我认为利率市场也是
suggesting that steepening in the curve. UBS joined us and they did also observe
表明曲线变陡。 瑞银加入了我们，他们也观察到
this somewhat slight repricing of inflation expectations in China going
这有点轻微的重新定价 中国通胀预期持续走高
into the last hour of the morning session here in Hong Kong.
到凌晨的最后一个小时 会议在香港举行。
We are, let's call it flat after opening lower session highs and then let's call
我们是，开张后就叫平吧 降低盘中高点，然后我们打电话
it even here, splitting the difference between the two MSCI Asia Pacific going
即使在这里，也能平分秋色 两者之间的 MSCI 亚太区走势
into a couple of market opens. You have Thailand and you have India
进入几个市场开放。 你有泰国，你有印度
bottom up your screens. Our futures, we're down 6/10 of 1%.
从下到上你的屏幕。 我们的期货下跌了 1% 的 6/10。
Weakness coming to the equity complex this Monday.
股市疲软 这个星期一。
Lots more ahead, though. This is the China show.
不过，还有很多事情要做。 这就是中国秀。